e e
[Music]
oh
welcome living Mana church family so
good to see all of you here uh today we
are looking forward to worshiping god
with you on this sabbath again it's such
a blessing to have all of you here uh
with us and we again are just excited
that it's a Sab that you are here
worshiping please put in the chat where
you're viewing from put a one in the
chat if this is your very first time
worshiping with living Mana Church how'
you guys like that uh intro were you
answering some of those questions I I
saw some of you answering those
questions and so uh that's always fun
around this time of year just to have uh
some fun true facts that you can answer
from the Bible so we are just happy to
have you here again with us amen man
yeah we definitely see you enjoying
those quizzes I think this is the second
week we've done it yes um and uh we're
probably going to continue that yeah and
we have one Jasmine is here with us for
the first time so Jasmine welcome to
living Mana Church please let us know
where you're viewing from Jasmine we are
so thrilled to have you we are a 100% um
online church and we have programming
all throughout the week mental health
physical health we have prayer um on
Wednesdays uh we have testimony
Thursdays um and Friday night um Friday
Night Lights for the Youth and so for
the yeah for the Youth and so and we
have children's programming on Sabbath
as well so
welcome yes uh we've got uh I think we
got a good service today yeah um we're
going to be doing question and answer
today question and answer yep so uh if
you have questions please um Bible
questions for him mental health
questions for me for the first timers I
am a licensed marriage and family
therapist so I'll just be answering some
mental health questions that you may
have not as your therapist but just as
your first lady Y and we've already got
a bunch of well at least I've already
got a bunch of questions in so and I I
got a really one I got one but a good
one to get the ball started like it's
something I love to talk about anyway so
so please put your mental health
questions in the chat and I will be
grabbing them as they come yeah and then
for the Divine Service uh we're going to
be continuing uh I'll be continuing my
nine part Series this is part
three of the nine things needed to stand
in the time of trouble so
um uh definitely let people know share
the link um this is a nine-part series
if you've missed part one and part two
just go back to see what we did last
week uh the sermon from last week and
the week before
um but uh I I believe you will be uh
highly blessed um by what you hear uh
from those two sermons and what you will
hear today praise God praise God we are
excited we're going to be talking about
this until it happens so if we're g if
you hopefully you don't get tired of us
talking about it because we're gonna be
talking about it until May 1 so that is
the
convocation some of you who are just
joining us haven't been here you might
like what convocation living Mana online
church that's a 100% online church is
actually going to be in person for the
very first time and that is May 1
through 4 so you have a few months to
plan and and get prepared but we want to
uh just let you know how you can
register for the convocation we want you
there we want to see you we want to meet
you this is going to be you're going to
have amazing uh speakers I'm pointing to
you because I yes you are one of the
speakers um and it's and we have a many
of our presenters here on living Mana uh
Church uh Dr White Lami
Richardson uh the prayer leaders which
is uh Terry and Amar you're going to get
to meet them and hear them as well we
have some other very exciting uh things
that are going to be happening I I'm
hearing right and understand we're going
to have a LM uh choir just for that
event so we know some of those uh
musicians that we get to hear sometimes
on alter live or through Power Wednesday
we get to hear you sing in a choir and
in person and even do some special
musics as well and we have uh another
music team coming to also support um
living Mana Church uh that's going to be
doing music all throughout the weekend
but we're going to have some of our
actual members and those are part of the
church in the choir and doing some
special music as well so we are excited
that's not it we have many many other
things but um I'll be telling you as as
we as we're preparing and announcing um
and I'd like to just put up that slide
um so that you can just know how to
register put a five in the chat if you
guys are
excited um and you know what it is first
well we I don't want to say first come
first serve but I we will you know we
don't want to you want to get yours you
want to register now and and book your
room or however you're going to do your
stay you want to do all of that so that
you will be there and uh it not fill up
too quickly um so I'm yeah so we're GNA
have
that
e e
all the different ways we can so through
text through sending you to Mighty
networks uh to get you to scan the QR
code here so there's just a variety of
ways and that slide will be back up
during the announcements for church and
so we are excited that's May 1 through
the 4th and we are going to have a
spiritual really good time and we are
going to have a just family community
bonding good time with good food good
music good preaching just fun guys it's
going to be a lot of fun so definitely
you want to be there yeah and I think
for some reason the sound may have went
out when the slide went up so they may
have missed some of what you said oh no
um and you'll hear it again yeah no
sound is it do you guys hear have sound
now put a one in the chat if you can
hear me now or if you majority of that
yeah all right I think they could hear
us now but uh I think when the side went
up your audio went out so see that's
that's the enemy yeah the enemy doesn't
want you guys to come so come I'm going
to repeat all of that again in in the
church service so so continue to worship
with us throughout the entire church
service don't go anywhere you don't want
to miss anything but um there's several
different ways you're going to get that
information again through Mighty
networks through a text and um by being
being here staying for church you will
uh get to see the QR code and you'll be
able to scan that yeah all right you're
looking at my shirt um Live Like Jesus
Love Like
Jesus oh no I'm sorry love like Jesus is
the whole thing Love Like Jesus is the
whole thing but that's good Live Like
Jesus Love Like Jesus um so yeah this is
the message for
today it was really I had didn't
pre-think about it like I normally do
but as I grabbed it and saw opened it up
I was like I just saw a gray shirt and I
was like okay let me see what this says
and then the Lord started speaking to me
um so um Love Like Love Like Jesus I
mean the times that we have we need to
Love Like Jesus always the times that it
is the most difficult is when you have
people not treating you like Jesus and
you want to respond in kind like they
are of course our carnal nature wants to
respond that way and so the
encouragement today is to love like
Jesus Love Like Jesus tap
into your your mature mind right your
mature Christian mind and I want you to
make sure that your mic is
on guys my mic was off thank you thank
you wow I've been talking through you
you've been talking through me hey guys
did you have you heard anything I've
said said clearly cuz I can um quickly
say the important things okay I'm not
okay wow my mic was off the entire time
wow okay I was looking at the comments
they were like you sound very low like
they say rookie mistake that's a rookie
mistake and I'm not a
rookie but that was a rookie mistake I
should have man I yeah all right
so let's just do the T-shirt the other
announcements I like Jesus go ahead you
all right right Love Like Jesus guys the
message that I believe God gave me today
for this t-shirt is it's the most it's
easy for us to Love Like Jesus when
somebody else is loving us like Jesus
but when someone else is not loving us
like Jesus that's when we are want to do
the same thing um and
it take a deep breath put yourself in a
time out before you respond and I know
that could like that could just take a
few seconds or maybe it takes a little
bit longer than that
but you need to tap into your mature
spiritual mind um to be able to respond
and to treat people and to Love Like
Jesus and to be able to do that because
our carnal nature will just want to lash
out and that's not what God wants us to
do and we feel better and we feel like
the bigger person because we are doing
the right thing and you actually get
peace and you feel better when you
respond that way you actually feel
really bad when you respond the other
way like sometimes we think like yeah I
told him I told
her and you feel horrible inside it
doesn't give you that peace it doesn't
give you that true happiness it just
continues the frustration and anger I'll
say it's uh you cannot Love Like Jesus
if you're not loving those that don't
love you back right if you love those
that love you back you're not loving
like Jesus right no you're just loving
people who are treating you very nicely
yeah and Jesus which is self-centered
love right and Jesus I love you if you
love me right Jesus died for us while we
were yet sinners and so love like that
guys love like love like that yep love
like that the people that are closest to
us it's the hardest for us to love like
that sometimes I mean they can trigger
us the most and make us the most upset
so yeah encouragement for today guys I
hate that I you guys didn't hear me all
that time but that's okay I talk again
I'll speak again during church time okay
all right so yes welcome again everyone
please um we've basically done the
welcomes but you guys can welcome each
other so put in the chat where you're
viewing from if you haven't done so
already and we are looking forward to
answering your questions today yep yep
uh we are going to uh we're going to
pray
yes and then we uh we're going to get
into these questions so let's do that
and again hopefully y'all can hear us
well I see some people saying my mic
sounds a little bit low my mic is on um
so uh probably because M they are so I
don't know yeah okay can hear now great
great all right so let's pray and then
let's let's get into these questions
Heavenly Father uh we thank you Lord for
giving us this day to Worship You Lord
we pray that uh you would help us Lord
to lay aside all our burdens all our
cares
and to focus in on worshiping you today
Lord um bless us Lord as we as we
worship you um and uh be with us as we
answer these questions Lord we pray this
in Jesus name amen and amen amen yes
we're taking Bible questions he has
quite a few I have one for mental health
questions um so please put in the chat
uh for mental health questions and if he
gets through the Bible questions pretty
quickly you can put more in there I have
a bunch I'm not getting through them
quickly please send me mental health
questions yeah okay all right so did you
want to did you have did you say you had
a question to to kind of kick it off or
I have a question so you want to start I
have one but you can start okay all
right all right so question number one
the first question I'm going to deal
with is this after reading Luke
23 um 20 uh
54 to
56 I they understand clearly that Jesus
was crucified on Friday rested in the
Tomb on Sabbath and Rose on Sunday uh
for it says that the women rested on
Sabbath according to the commandment and
that and that day can be no other than
the seventh day Sabbath of the fourth
Commandment but my question is about
Luke 24:1 which says now on the first
day of the week early in the morning I
understand clearly that this is the day
following the Sabbath but the word in
Greek used for day of the week is
sabbaton which means Sabbath so it reads
now on the first Sabbath early in the
morning in the
Greek is there a mistake here or could
this be a reference to the first fruit
Sabbath that was on the 16th of Nissan
that year uh please help me out because
there is Messianic Jew attending our
Sabbath School who is using this to try
to prove that Jesus was not crucified on
Friday evening um so I think the answer
to this is pretty simple um that word
word uh
Sabaton it's
translated the same way in all the
verses that describe Jesus rising uh on
that day after the
Sabbath and you're kind of like well why
do these verses translated uh on the
first day of the week
versus how it is being suggested here
now on the first Sabbath early in the
morning
the reason why is because this word is
used at least once to literally mean
weak and we find that in Luke
18:12 where
uh the Bible is describing you know an
individual who is talking about how many
times he fasts and the text says Luke
18:12 I fast twice in the week and I
give tithe of all that I possess
the word here used is Sabaton same
word so we got two options here either
this man speaking is saying I F I fast
twice on Sabbath or he's actually saying
I fast twice during the
week we have no we can come to no other
conclusion but
that this word
also means
week with that in mind when we go back
to Luke chapter 24 verse1 and it says
now on the
first of Sabaton the Sabaton now you see
why it is almost uniformally translated
as the first of the
week the the argument that this is the
first of a new Sabbath or the first
Sabbath of the no none of those
arguments arguments stand because the
text is literally saying just what it's
translated as it was a first of the week
the first of the week so um hopefully
that that helps you just reference Luke
18:12 where you see the same word being
used as a man describes that he fasts
twice during the week not twice on
Sabbath okay so that's question number
one do you want me to go go to another
question or good question but I just saw
someone say that they're GRS I can go to
my next I know you have a lot but
whenever a young person asked something
I just think we should they go to the
top of the list um someone said my
grandson had a Bible question about who
was the first prophet in
Genesis who was the first prophet in
Genesis
um I know you were looking at me I'm
like like looking at you like I mean the
the first recognized Prophet is going to
be Noah yes but before Noah there's
there's Enoch but Enoch never actually
you don't find Enoch's prophecy
until um you get to the book of
Jude right so but the first technically
Enoch but then Noah prophesied so no was
the first one to give a prophecy of
here's what's going to happen right a
global prophecy
so um yeah I would say technically
Enoch but the first actual Prophecy of
the not the first Prophecy of the Bible
there's the first Prophecy of the Bible
is given in Genesis 3:15 by God himself
um but Noah would be the first one to
prophesy of a major event so um there is
your answer yes all right um all right
so did you
did you want to go to your question or
do you want me to cuz I
got you could do one more one more yeah
okay all right and you can be looking as
uh okay as other questions come in
okay so second question is this there
Pastor IO I read this morning during my
Bible study act no this is not a rerun
we are live no we are live we are live
please
share we're live okay brother Tennessee
Okay so dear Pastor I read this morning
during my Bible study Acts 13:33
uh where it says God has fulfilled this
for us their children in that he has
raised up Jesus also oh as it is also
written in the second Psalm you are my
son today I have begotten you do I
understand this correctly that from
Jesus resurrection only that he is
called the begotten Son of God before
that he was just called the Son of God
if so then begotten makes so much sense
so yes you are
actually uh you're actually correct
um Jesus is prophetically called the
begotten Son of God way before he became
the begotten Son of
God um this is what the text is actually
saying um if you if you read the text
again I'm going to read it again God has
fulfilled this for us their children in
that he has raised up
Jesus he talking about recognizing him
as the only begotten son and he's saying
this has been fulfilled in that he has
raised up Jesus right let me go to
Hebrews chapter 1 verse5 just to just to
amplify this point in Hebrews 1 ver5 it
says For unto which of the Angels said
he at any time Thou Art my son this day
have I begotten thee so there was a day
that Jesus was begotten mhm and we got
two options either that day was sometime
back in eternity P which we know it
can't be because the Bible says in in in
the very next
verse6 again when he bringeth in the
first begotten into the world he saith
let all the angels of God worship
him
if as some people say this was way way
way back in eternity that means that
Angels were present when Jesus was
begotten
because the text says when the son of
when the Son of God is brought into the
world when the begotten was brought into
the world God said to the angels let all
the Angels worship Him the Angels were
there to worship the begotten
son so this cannot
reference an event that happened in the
past that
day was his
resurrection that day in fact more
specifically is when Jesus enters into
heaven so let me show you this in P in
Psalms
2:1 um the Bible says why do the Heathen
rage and the people imagine a vain thing
the kings of the earth set themselves
and the rulers take counsel against the
Lord and against his anointed saying let
us break their bands asunder and cast
their cords from us so Psalms 2 verse
1-3 is talking about the people of the
earth Gathering against the Lord's
anointed let's keep reading he that sth
in the heavens shall laugh the Lord
shall have them in derision then shall
he speak unto them in his wrath and Vex
them in his sore
displeasure verse six yet have I set my
king upon my Holy Hill of Zion when did
he do
that after the kings of the earth raged
against this anointed
one so Psalms 2 talks about this raging
against the anointed one but God is
going to raise him up right to sit on
his throne His Holy Hill in Zion verse 7
then says I will declare the decree the
Lord has said unto me thou art my son
this day have I begotten
thee that beginning was a beginning from
the dead when Jesus enters into the when
Jesus enters into the Heavenly courts
this is when God said let all the angels
of God worship him let me give you just
uh let me give you one more verse two
more verses while you're looking for
that verse I just want to say welcome
to um from I'm missing the name but from
Serbia I don't think we've ever had
somebody from Serbia so just want to
welcome um yeah I don't know how to say
the the name but welcome we're happy to
have you here go ahead okay um so
blessed 1 Peter 1:3 blessed be the God
and father of our Lord Jesus Christ
which of according to His abundant Mercy
has begotten us again unto a lively Hope
by the resurrection of Jesus Christ from
the dead so we are
begotten by the resurrection of Christ
from the dead notice Revelation 15 which
says and from Jesus Christ who is a
faithful witness and the first begotten
of the dead and the prince of the kings
of the earth so the Bible over and over
recognizes this beginning as something
that occurs at the resurrection of
Christ we can say it like
this the begotten Son of God think of it
think of it this way and it's a really
it's kind of like a and I've preached
about this before but think about Jesus
the man Jesus Christ his 33 and a half
years of life was almost like
his time in the
womb the completed man from his birth as
a child up to his 33 and a half
years his death burial and resurrection
that ascended man is the begotten Son of
God the whole man he had to walk he had
to be the pattern for mankind he had to
live it completed 33 and A2 years
perfectly and then he dies and then he
resurrects and this this Resurrection is
almost as it were his birth so when a
woman has a child you know the child is
is nine I about three nine months in the
womb and then he's born think of Jesus's
life as being in the womb he is being
formed this new man is being formed this
new prototype of what those who believe
in him will become that is what is
happening with Jesus for that 33 and 1/2
years he dies he's buried and then the
resurrected man the new man as it were
becomes the Prototype this is my
begotten son begotten from the dead okay
yes all right good question so good
answer do you want to take a question or
I can yes I have I have questions um so
I'm going to do the very first one that
came in um first
so um this was this is a great question
and it's what I love to talk to believe
it or not to my clients about because
it's something that's so important but
it's just looked over like it's nothing
but it's but it's everything um all
right so somebody asked e they said what
type of exercise is best for physical
and mental health and how to implement
that with a busy schedule okay first of
all we're going to go back to why
exercise is so important when we're
dealing with mental health with physical
health I think we all understand why
it's important to exercise um but with
but we don't put that we don't always
connect that to mental health and this
is so huge and I tell my clients like
I'm not a medical doctor right but if I
were just to never do some psycho
education on what how exercise affects
or not not having proper exercise
affects ffects the mental health I'm
doing them a disservice it's almost like
a wash if you will like I'm here trying
to give you tools on how to deal with
your anxiety and depression and
relationship issues and whatever you're
bringing in but if I don't talk about
the importance of exercise and how that
affects your mind and how that actually
if if you are not having proper exercise
you are going to be more prone for
anxiety and depression and you're not
going to be having the dopamine or your
serotonin levels are not going to be at
that proper level for you to feel good
and um not be as depressed and those
type of things truly as a mental health
professional I'm doing you a disservice
so number one that's why exercise is
important for your mental health because
when you exercise 30 minutes of
cardiovascular exercise a day helps
releases your mind your brain will
release
dopamine and those serotonin connection
and all that gets released as well and
so that's your healthy happy hormones
right so that's what you want that's
what makes you feel good that makes you
be able to feel like you can take on the
day um and even though things may not be
going perfectly right you're able to
deal with the stress in a better way and
that helps your your mental health so
there's no particular I don't know why
I'm looking at you but there's no
particular uh cardio exercise that you
have to do you just need to be doing
cardio that could just be walking
walking 30 minutes a day of course you
can run run you could cycle you could do
whatever you enjoy doing but it is
really important and you said how do you
do that and you have a really busy
schedule we all have very busy schedules
but we make sure we get up and we do
what we take a shower we brush our teeth
we wash our face we eat we take time to
eat like put it in you have to put your
exercise in that category you're going
to just not not eat or by God's grace
not take a shower wash your face or
brush your teeth or any of those things
like you know you have to do those
things for your hygiene and so your
exercise is just as important as that so
put it in that category and you have to
make sure that you do it and you're
going to be blessed physically as I tell
people physically mentally spiritually
exercise is you're G to get it all so y
that's why it's very important
absolutely absolutely all right so
please put your mental continue to put
your mental health questions in the chat
and I will answer yeah good
answer so this is a family question oh
um go ahead so this person says I feel
paralyzed to serve God when my own
family knows better and isn't doing
better how can I go out and serve God
when I have so much guilt over my own
family being lost I feel like a
hypocrite or that I'm leaving my family
behind to go help other people
so no I mean okay well I mean I'm I can
go first go
okay I felt like it was your question I
thought it was my question no I was well
all I was going it was sent to me but I
think it's a you know it's it's a SL
mental health spiritual question I mean
it goes with both so let me say this I
would say
that you know we are only responsible
for other people up to a certain point
talking about the family right right
anybody right your family your your your
spouse your children um
you have to realize that salvation needs
to be worked out on an individual
basis and you know I think
if if we carry that attitude of well I
can't Minister I can't serve other
people
because um you know everybody in my
family my children or my
spouse um then it would just be I think
it would be a whole lot of people who
aren't doing would be doing anything
aren't doing anything mhm so I think the
important thing is you got to pray you
work think about
this there are ways to work for your
children ways to work for your family
without
necessarily they may not want to hear
your preaching they may not want to hear
your but you can pray for them so pray
and work and do what God's called you to
do but pray for your your spouse pray
for your children pray for your
grandchildren like that's don't think of
it as oh it's just praying right that's
a lot and just be that example I mean
you
know my t-shirt Love Like Jesus like let
them see Jesus in
every inch of you like let them just see
like like so when so you're basically
being that example for God of his
character to make them to want to get
the god that you serve they going to
want to get to know him better and all
of your family is on their own Journey
don't think that God's not seeing
everything and he doesn't have a
salvational plan for them individually
it may not look the way that you think
it should look and you know because God
he just know he he's going to go out of
his way to to save them and things may
happen that you I don't God is just a
unique God so he will save and be unique
and create the way that he has to do it
for each family member so you just
continue to love like Jesus love them
like Jesus would be that example um you
are just the Practical form you are to
be that walking Jesus or Bible in their
life so that they're just like man I
want to read the Bible more I want to
get to know this Jesus more and then
keep praying and let God do what he's
going to do with those individuals that
is not um a criteria or a deal breaker
that oh you're family is not following
um God so you can't go out and witness
to other people like like you said like
a lot of people would not be in Ministry
if that was the case so everybody has to
have an individual relationship with God
so we have four children our four
children are not saved off of our
relationship with God they have to have
their own indiv individual relationship
with him and the same for your family
and your children and um just love them
and enoy enjoy this ride even though we
all want our children and family members
to be in a relationship with close
relationship with God and be working in
the church and be right there with us
just enjoy the ride that that just have
the faith that of the ride that God the
faith ride there it is the faith ride
that God has your family on um and you
get to have the F front row seat of what
God is going to do in their lives and
it's p perspective changed too like um
and I'm not calling you prideful please
don't M misunderstand that but sometimes
we have a sense of Pride especially in
Ministry it's like we're out here like
teaching to the world um that to to come
to to serve God and that all of these
things and so if one of our family
members is like doing something
different you could easily have some
pride of like you know you're my child
or you're my brother or you're my sister
whatever how are you doing this and I'm
out here preaching this you got to let
that all go and just they're all their
own journey and they're an individual
and and God knows that you know you're
preaching and teaching to other people
um should not
be um seen through shouldn't be seen
negatively through your eyes or anybody
else's eyes if your family or loved one
is not following God so P perspective
change yeah all right we got a couple
more questions kind of like this
but here's another question is it
against the Sabbath to socialize or do
fun things that are biblical like
watching Christian movies or playing
Bible
games perfectly fine that's my perfectly
fine it's that's perfectly fine oh you
know whatsoever things lead you to to
focus on God uh do those things so right
that's the point of the Sabbath if
something yeah if something just like
nature going out on a walk you might do
that during the week but doing that on
Sabbath is even more meaningful because
God is all in nature and watching a
Bible MO movie that's about God that's
having your mind on God on the Sabbath
and playing Bible games that these Tri
trivia questions that we put in the um
in the intro I
mean I mean you're not playing against
anybody but you know you're you know it
it's a game but it's about God the whole
thing is God wants him to be on your
mind always but in those 24 hours he
wants you to block everything else out
and just him so if you do that through a
movie Bible Christian movie if you do
that through game playing you know
Christian games and those type of things
that are about God it's perfectly fine
yeah all right so here is another
question um and I will uh I will deal
with this question it's kind of along
the same lines it's a more personal
question okay um but it's a pretty
relevant and hottish
question so this person says I don't
like to attend my home church anymore
because of the political environment
this has been increasingly getting worse
since
2016 I feel like such a hypocrite when I
go to support my family and smile and
greet people but I know I have bad
feelings towards them I appreciate how
Pastor Iva presents the issue but not
everyone does it that way and it's
created very negative feelings in me
toward the people in my home
Church um so he's basically asking what
do I do about these feelings how do I
handle this situation and I have to say
I'm going to be preaching about um not
this particularly but uh the nine things
that are needed um to stand in a time of
trouble and we're on part three I'm
going to be addressing this this
today realize
that the shirt Love Like Jesus we talked
about a tante shirt a little bit earlier
Love Like Jesus
um this is where loving like Jesus comes
in
right this is where
despite um how you may be
negatively
treated especially in light of the stuff
we see going on in the church
today this is what this is what it means
to Love Like
Jesus
when people disagree with
you
um
and just have that negative spirit and
attitude you're not you're not down with
me well I'm canceling you I'm cutting
you off uh you know you're lost and
you're hopeless if you reciprocate recip
reciprocate crate uh having hard
time with that
mentality um you
are you're you're you're demonstrating
The Same Spirit and it becomes easy to
to think that you're doing the right
thing and you may be right you may have
the right position but have the wrong
spirit and so it is absolutely important
and listen I I know what it feels like
over this very
issue right I know what it feels like to
post a video video and have people come
up in the chat Pastor Mars we don't
listen to you anymore you you this you
that and I will be honest the the carnal
part of me is
like what the flesh part of
me not that I want to respond and and be
like you know you don't know what you're
talking about but there is that hurtful
The Flash wants to respond that way yeah
but there is that hurtful like but then
you're yeah y wait you don't understand
right and and if we could just talk and
you could understand then I'm sure you
wouldn't think or you wouldn't say what
you're
saying so it's
okay to
be it's okay to to have that sorrow if
you will that man why are things like
this but if you reciprocate
with
anger with you know what your law
I'm cutting you off
um it's the wrong
spirit and you don't want to be of the
very same
spirit that you say is a negative Spirit
right so practicing that love that Mercy
that
forgiveness and that openness to always
be
willing to say yeah okay
we we let's talk this
through that's the spirit that that is
necessary if you're trying to
reflect the character of Jesus right the
spirit of
Jesus and the devil is going to make it
hard he wants to make it hard to reflect
that spirit and how's he going to do
that by making the people who say these
things and who who you know speak
against you and and are against you
making them the most obnoxious you know
how how can I get them to be as
obnoxious as I can toward you or when
they're factually wrong or when they're
factually wrong and saying things that
are you know that are not you said this
huh we automatically want to defend
ourselves
yeah where Jesus never
did yeah we didn't
defending
truth and defending self it's different
two different
things so
again make sure that your heart is right
make sure that it's not you like okay
I'm gonna you know I'm defending
me defend
truth defend
Truth All right so you got a question
question okay answer yes there was
someone asked
um how do you what do you do or how do
you reach someone who is showing signs
of
depression um how can you help them
basically the question was and you know
it depends on how close you are to them
if this is a family member or a spouse
or a really good friend and you're close
if you're close to someone you can
definitely
um you
know in an empathetic way obviously you
know just really you're you're off
you're close to them so they already
know that you love them right and so you
can go to them and say hey I can tell
that you're going through some hard
times right now or you know I can you
know just see that things just are or
you could just say like things just
don't seem to be the same with you or I
see you you know isolating yourself or
just you don't ever smile that much or
you just really seem unhappy or whatever
and you're close enough to them that you
can just inquire like that or just
mention that and maybe they'll open up
to you and when they open up to you just
a little bit because you're not trying
to be their therapist or their mental
health provider but you just want them
to know like U obviously not provider
but you're just not their therapist but
um you just want them to know that you
are are here for them if they just want
to you're just here to listen not to
judge them or tell them what to do but
just here to listen and then in that
encourage them to reach out to a mental
health professional that can can help
them uh get through whatever difficult
time they are that they're are going
through and also to obviously let them
know that you are praying for them and
that is the most important thing that
you are praying for them and that they
feel safe with you and as they hopefully
they will be getting better but if they
continue to go down this road and get
worse at least you're a safe person that
they can come and talk to so you just
want to make sure that they know that
you are you are here for them this is a
safe space um and when they do come try
to lead them to get the help that they
need um during this
time all right
yeah okay okay um and I'm also a part of
the mental health questions is
relationship so marriage questions
please
send them they're my favorite type of
questions yeah I just saw there's a
question there that you may want to look
at it and address next but uh let's go
to this question uh who is who is this
referring to in Daniel
9:26 the people of the prince sh the
people of the prince that shall come so
the question is in Daniel 9:26 let me
read Daniel 9:26 it says after three
scoring two weeks shall Messi be cut off
but not for himself and the people of
the prince that shall come shall destroy
the city and the sanctuary and the end
thereof shall be with a flood and until
the end of the war desolations are
determined so the question is who is
this
Prince that shall
come whose people shall destroy the city
and the
sanctuary so um there
are two ways to look at this
verse
um the the prince that shall
come
um for a lot of a lot of people see this
Prince as the
Messiah um particularly
because in several verses before this
you see you know the whole 70E prophecy
is about the Messiah the prince the
prince um and his coming at a certain
period of
time so there many people who believe
that the prince the people of the prince
that shall
come uh were the
Jews and they were the people of
Jesus
um I'm going to say my position on this
is
that this Prince is actually
Satan let me give you the reason why
because in Daniel
9:26 the first half of the verse talks
about the Messiah being cut
off and then it's almost as if it says
and after he is cut off so after three
score and two weeks shall Messiah be cut
off but not for himself and the people
of the prince that shall come shall
destroy the city in the sanctuary so I
want you to notice my emphasis on the
word shall
come the people of the prince that shall
come so the first half of nine 26 says
after three score in two weeks Messiah
is going to be cut
off and then there's a prince that shall
come so messiah's cut off but there's a
prince that is
coming now does this fit at all with
what actually happened and Jesus's own
words let me show you in John 14:30
Jesus says this Hereafter I will not
talk talk much with you so why is he
saying I will not talk talk much with
you he's saying this because he's about
to die and his very next words are this
for the prince of this world cometh and
has nothing in
me all right put a one in the chat if
you understand what I just
shared Jesus is about to
die Daniel 9:26 a and there is a prince
that is coming Daniel 9:26 B
in fact in John 12:31 Jesus said
this now is the Judgment of this world
now shall the prince of this world be
cast out and I if I be lifted up will
draw all men unto me all men unto me
this he said signifying what death he
should die so he's literally
saying I'm about to die but there's a
prince coming
this Prince is about to be cast out we
see that again in Revelation
12:7 Michael and his angels they were
cast
out I'm not going to get into all
because there was a casting out at the
beginning you know with the war in
heaven and there was a casting out at
the
cross
but what's happening in Daniel 9:26 is
something very subtle the people of the
prince that shall come destroy the city
in the sanctuary that's the
Romans but it's also now the Jewish
people because remember what have they
done they've rejected the
Messiah and they've said we have no King
but
Caesar in Revelation 12 the
dragon is
personified in the Roman
Empire so when those Jewish leaders said
we have no King but
Caesar they were were saying we're down
with
Rome it is their rejection of the
Messiah and the Romans who ultimately
came in and destroyed Jerusalem and the
temple them together are the people of
the prince that would come which was
Satan himself because of their rejection
of the
Messiah the city and the temple was
destroyed so that's how I read Daniel
9:26 Daniel 9:26 a
the Messiah will be cut
off B A Prince Will
Come and Jesus himself identified who
that Prince was and those who followed
him were the ones responsible for the
destruction of the city and the
Temple and
so yeah so I I'll leave that answer
there I'll leave now if you are of the
belief that the prince is
Jesus and the people of the prince would
be the Jews who rejected Jesus it's
still kind of the same thing there's not
a whole it's really in a sense a
technical difference because the end
result is that they destroy the temple
and the city whether it was the Jews
that brought it on themselves or the
Romans that did it but for me to be
accurate that
Prince is the prince that would come
after after the death and Resurrection
uh the death and resurrection of Jesus
Christ or I should say the death of
Jesus Christ when when the prince of
this world was cast out all right you go
ahead okay um so we have a question how
do you help someone with psychotic
symptoms for instance is delusional or
presents with
hallucinations when and how can you help
gently challenge their perceptions like
yeah no you don't do that you don't do
that because they're obviously not
thinking straight and correctly so you
do what I have to do I'm not a medical
doctor or and I'm not a psychiatrist I
so as a therapist if someone is
presenting with those type of symptoms
then I'm going to have to refer them to
a medical doctor and a psychiatrist um
because they need to be on medication so
talk therapy um or even a friend or a
family member is not going to be able to
um talk them out of having delusions and
hallucinations so there's things going
wrong in the mind and the Brain um that
needs to um be dealt with now if they're
on the medication then then they can
come back to me and we can we can uh
work on some things if they're on the
medication that's helping them with the
hallucinations and delusions and those
type of thing so it's not uh that's not
something that we can we can just talk
to somebody about and they're going to
snap out of it no it's a it's a
condition uh that they need medication
for okay and
then brother Tennessee he took my uh
encouragement literally okay thank you
brother Tennessee this is what I wanted
okay so he says well I'm going to ask
I've been asking the Lord if the woman I
have been dating currently
um currently dating is the one but I get
silence but it appears as though my
character is tested dealing with her wow
that's such a a big question like before
the fact that your character is tested
um probably nobody would get married if
that's the case like meaning meaning I'm
about I'm about to I'm about to know I'm
about to go backwards I just wanted to
talk I just wanted to like uh say that
uh because in marriage AG I mean you're
two you're two individuals and you're
becoming one and sometimes that
combining of the Oneness sometimes not
sometimes okay your character is going
all the time is going to be tested yeah
because you okay thank you you're the
two coming together is like iron
sharpening iron right so that's a but if
it's if it's a bad way go ahead yeah
that's what I'm saying so that's natural
that's natural for some you know like
you see things this way she sees it this
way how are you going to respond you
know what was her how or what
is yeah how does she deal with conflict
how do you deal with conflict I mean
those need to be in healthy forms for
there to be a healthy marriage and I
know you're not married you're just
dating however now going backwards to
your question at from the beginning part
of your question if um the person that
you're dating you're saying
like you need to be asking yourself okay
so is this person drawing me closer to
God does she inspire me does this in
this relationship am I inspired to to
pray more to study the Bible more is is
do we like do you see that this
relationship is um something that you
can see Jesus in the center of it um if
there's a lot of if you're dating and
there's a lot of arguing and there's a
lot of conflict and you're not even
married yeah big red flag because it's
not going to get easy in marriage if
anything marriage will just be like all
right let's take those things to the
next level honestly honestly so um and
I'll be honest as as a a therapist
I have couples that come that are just
dating and they're it's always they're
already in a rough patch and it's so
difficult and this and that and the
other and I think I've said this before
here but I'll just be honest like in
those situations like yes I'm here to to
help but if it's already this hard
it's probably just not a right fit this
is not and I'm not telling you that I'm
not speaking for God to you brother
Tennessee that God has to tell you that
because I have no idea what's going on
in that relationship but in other
circumstances if it's
so difficult
dating again marriage is not going to
make that easier yeah if if you're being
challenged to be better that's a good
sign because maybe you need to grow as a
person right if you're challenged if
you're being
challenged to refrain from getting worse
then that's probably a bad sign yeah if
you're
like like you I want to I want to curse
right now because the relationship
brings you so much lower yeah then it's
probably best to not proceed in that
relationship if you're being challenged
to be a better person to be a better man
to be a better woman to you know to come
up higher yeah um that's that's that's
good and I like this response somebody
put in the chat I've learned that when
God is silent it's because he really
gave me the answer there you go sister
Maya good to see you amen amen um but
yeah Amen to that comment too because
that was great yeah that was great and
and just brother Tennesse you you know
like the Holy Spirit and how the Holy
Spirit speaks to
you um so just continue to pray to God
and just
yeah let the Holy Spirit speak to you
he's here to guide and he will do and He
will definitely do that all right so I
saw a question and I think it was more I
don't know if it was a so much a
question as it
was I'm just GNA it was dealing with uh
tongues specifically yeah I saw that too
I thought I was like oh it's a great
question yeah you GNA answer it and uh I
think the question is not so much okay
like like um the question is really how
do I respond
to uh family members who believe
something
different
than than I
do doctrinally speaking that you may
even feel you know and believe rightly
so yeah this is you know this is not of
God this is demonic or what have you uh
and it's kind of the same thing I was
saying about dealing with church members
who you know own church family who
believes something that you don't
believe not doctrinally but
just as a way of life right um that
causes
tension you have
to you have to be able to your
love has to be able to elevate you to a
place of
peace right where you're like look I
understand I'm not going to allow myself
to get worked up and get angry
right
at you know this person these people
whether it's my church family or my
blood
family
um because I know better I'm going to
have the patience of Jesus right Jesus
wasn't going around getting mad at you
know the people that were
that were under deception uh even the
Pharisees they couldn't get them
mad so that's
pretty think about think about that
remember we're not
Jesus
right um but we're called to be like
him
so pray
that's right don't get carried away
that's what the devil is trying to
do
um the devil's trying to get us carried
away through other people through their
you know sometimes their
mean-spiritedness or sometimes their
they're they're being led astray
themselves you can have the right
position and express it in the wrong
way and therefore do damage to the
people you're trying to minister to and
do damage to
yourself
so um that's what I would say right you
brought up tongues as the example but it
can be anything it could be you know my
family members believe that Sunday's a
Sabbath it it can be
anything God says I need you to love
those that don't agree with you I need
you to love those that don't see things
the way that you do um and and listen
y'all this is so
crucial when people miss this
point it becomes easy to hate the enemy
and if you hate the enemy you have
lost you have
lost this is why the spirit that is so
present in Christianity today and I'm
talking about you
know well I at one time would have said
out side of adventism but no
Christianity
today for some reason has accepted this
P that we can hate the enemy are you gay
we can hate you Mercy are you are you
are you Pro this or anti this we can
hate you we can mock you we can it's
okay for us to do
this that Spirit has entered into our
church and it's infecting
it is like a
virus and it is
infecting millions of so-called
Christians devil doesn't care how he
infects you as long as he infects
you the only way to be inoculated
against that
virus is to be
inoculated
with love
it is to be it is to have love flowing
through your
veins and if you have love flowing
through your veins Godly love agape
love you're not going to be infected by
that which is
infecting
millions of
professed
Christians today
I'll be preaching a sermon on that I
just discovered you
just called the
virus and the vaccine oh don't you she's
telling me don't do that don't you dare
don't do that don't do that don't you
call well preach it just don't call it
that just don't call it the virus and
the vaccine yeah just don't call it that
um I saw a good question I can't I saw
it float up and I okay I it it um and I
have another question but that one just
floated up um but it said how do you
deal with spiritual
depression
um I don't know exactly for sure the
context you asking that question but
um I just believe that when we truly
know the character of
God we don't experience spiritual
depression even though so we may be you
know messing up or not doing God's will
or that type of thing but when you
really know the character of God then
you know that you can come back and you
can repent and you can or you know or
it's just you know I think when we don't
have understand the character of God
that's when we do experience some
spiritual depression because we think
like I'm not good
enough um I'm not holy enough I'm not
doing all the right things sometimes
you know what I'm saying like we think
God is actually looking at every
single God wants Holiness in our life
right but he but he has the burden of
working that in us we just have to have
faith and allow um him to come in and
organize the furniture if you will of
our hearts you know what I mean it's
like put the burden back on God and he
will do it nothing's too hard for him
nothing's too it's not too much for him
and then you will have a perspective and
a perspective shift that will have you
looking at God like all right God you
know I know I'm a sinner um you know I'm
this this and that um but I'm giving my
heart to you and I'm allow you to work
you know that just changes so that we're
not in like a depression and thinking
every day like beating yourself up
because you you know you sinned and did
that or or whatever you had not a great
thought or you didn't feel like loving
the person like Jesus I mean it's not
that God can't change that and he wants
you to he does want you to do that but
he's not here to just beat you up you
guys have we have to God extends so much
grace to us and gives us the power to do
what we need to do but we need to learn
to extend Grace to ourselves because I
think we beat ourselves up wait we're
doing what God is not doing to ourselves
and that's how we experience spiritual
depression not sure if that's exactly
how you were asking it but that's what
God put on my heart and that's what I
yeah that's what I believe Christians go
through yeah they go through some
spiritual depression I have another this
will be my last question
um we can close it off with this okay
yeah okay um somebody asked to go over
the different um secure I'm sorry I'm
naming one of the Styles the attachment
Styles um and for those of you who are
not familiar with attachment Styles I
think I've answered this before but um
the attachment Styles is it's something
that is created when you are are are
born and you whoever your primary
caregiver is if they um if they are like
if you have a care a caregiver like your
mom and your dad that is showing you
lots of love and hugs and cuddling and
you will have a secure attachment and
that's that's one of the attachment
Styles and I'll go over them more but so
a secure you can have a secure you can
create a secure attachment style you can
create an anxious attachment style a
dismissive attachment style um
attachment style and a fearful avoidant
ATT disorganized attachment style so
it's pretty self-explanatory but
somebody who uh has that loving primary
caregiver at Birth and they in that in
the that infant stage and they are
showing them love and like I said the
all of that means a lot to to an infant
like the hugs and the kisses and the
they feel secure so that person that
attachment style those people seem to go
through life and have you know secure
they're secure in their relationships um
they're secure in how so relationship
doesn't have to just mean like with your
husband or your wife but you know your
relationship with anybody you um are
secure you know when you need to exit
out of those relationships and you know
when you need to stay and you're able to
uh just have healthy relationships then
the anxious
preoccupied they are very anxious in a
relationship again any relationship like
they're just not secure so they
overthink or they think
um you know you might be a people
pleaser which is an issue if you have if
you have an anxious attachment style uh
because you're just not secure that
people are are thinking good of you or
everybody's looking at you or they don't
really love you or I better do this so
to make them love me all of these type
of things so that's like some an example
of anxious um attachment style and then
dismissive they have a hard time um
avoidant dismissive of getting into
relationships and committing to
something or allowing themselves to
connect because uh they just don't allow
themselves to do that which is very
close cl to a fearful avoidant because
there's fear because maybe you were
abandoned or something happened in your
you know in those younger years that
helped to create this type of attachment
style they just aren't secure like the
first one we talked about so they have
fear that you know something's going to
happen uh if I let myself get too close
to someone or even when they do get
close there's still a wall up that
doesn't allow that person to completely
come in and connect so there's always
just a little bit bit of distance just
trying to protect themselves just enough
because they've been hurt um or they
just were not in a safe
situation and so there's a lot more we
could do a whole thing on that yeah
matter of fact think of mental health
Monday we should do attachment Styles I
think we did do something in the first
season but I think we need to do it
again and go deeper so hopefully that
was that helped yeah and made sense
yep all right well I know there's a lot
more questions in the chat we see them
but we're we're out of time we please
save them for the next question answer
we will do it we know we always do this
at least once a month yeah I see the
question on impersonating the dead and
can that be in uh included in the
blueprint um I see some other questions
as well I we we recognize your questions
we just don't have time to answer those
but uh but save those yeah or send those
into at tante Living mana. Church send
those questions please um to the email
that on our next go yeah that was good
questions yeah definitely put in Mighty
networks put it somewhere so we can see
it know that we are working on um the
blueprint documentary yeah Power of the
L ministri is is doing that it has
really come along nicely and uh so keep
that in prayer um but yeah if you have
20 Questions send your 20 Questions send
in 20 Questions yes we love doing these
question and answer times and we uh it's
really yeah we love to do it it's a lot
of fun for us and we think that it's
extremely helpful because you don't
always get to ask those questions and
you really really really want to know so
uh pray that it was a blessing we just
want to pray and then we um have uh we
want to talk about membership uh
transfers and those things right after
our prayer all right heavenly father
thank you Lord for again giving us this
time Lord to just uh Fellowship Lord uh
to dialogue ask questions and have them
answered
Lord um bless us now as we move into our
divine service and uh Lord especially
this message coming up on um uh part
three of nine things needed to stand in
the time of trouble Lord help us to
understand the importance uh of this
message Lord and um we pray I pray that
it will bless those that will that are
watching live and that will watch
afterward Lord and again we thank you
for your love for us in Jesus name we
pray amen amen amen so yes we are you
know many of you have always asked say
Hey how do I can how can I become a
member of living manage church and there
are three ways to do that you can um you
can if you are already a member of a
7day Adventist Church you can ask to
have your membership transferred and so
we're going to put up a slide here so
you can know where to to send that um
information to but if you uh have
already been baptized um and you are
already a member of another denomination
but you're learning about uh seventh day
adventism and you want to join you can
do that by Prof profession of Faith or
you can decide if you want to you can
get baptized and those are the three
ways that you can become a member um and
that email that you see there Patrice
living mana. live that is the email that
you can send um that you send to her um
any one of those three ways that you
want to become a member is through
profession of Faith baptism or to
transfer your membership speaking of
that we have uh some membership
transfers these are the first reading
and so we are going to put that slide up
now so that you uh can see those first
readings um for the membership
transfers and yep that's not the
slide there's actually a slide with two
two names one coming in and one
going out so we will provide that here
for you and for
that I will need to put on my glasses
we'll need to put on my glasses all
right so we
have we have Lis beeth rapael she is
transferring out to Princeton 7th Day
Adventist Church and again these are
first readings and we are and then we
have Robert Green who is transferring
would like to transfer into living Mana
church and that's from the Santa Cruz
7th Day Adventist Church so those are
our two first reading um first reading
membership transfers for today and we
will have the second reading next week
so with that said please if you are
interested in transferring your
membership or becoming a member in the
other ways please send an email to
Patrice living mana. live and that's how
you get that ball rolling please
continue to worship with us as we are
going into the Divine worship service
did you want to say anything about your
sermon yeah just uh go ahead and let
people know the sermon is coming up tell
them they don't want to miss this hit
that uh share button and uh by the way
if you have not subscribed to the living
Mana YouTube channel uh please uh do so
uh you'll get
notifications um when we go live and uh
yeah look forward to our worshiping with
you in a Divine service yes all right so
stay tuned continue to worship with
us on the northeast coast of the
beautiful Indonesian island of Bali is a
small coast of fishing Village that
contains a historical Relic that is
larger than life a rare piece of History
hidden just off of the shoreline just a
few meters below the ocean surface it is
one of the most beautiful and magical
iCal places to visit in all of Bali a
place to remember the past to be in awe
of the present and to learn the lessons
essential for a hopeful future a
shipwreck from the second world war
lying in a watery grave that reminds us
of the power of living for a purpose and
leaving a legacy that is larger than
life the USS Liberty was the United
States cargo ship built in New Jersey in
1918 this ship has had a very difficult
life but in every season and
Circumstance it has continued to serve a
meaningful purpose this ship served in
the first and second world wars as a
cargo ship for the United States
military aiding in the fight for Freedom
around the world but it Ral from
Australia to the Philippines in 1942 she
was hit Square on by a Japanese
submarine torpedo though damage Beyond
repair she was saved from immediate
sinking toed by the surrounding boats
and beached right here on the rocky
shores of Northeast Bali in the
Indonesian town of tulen though she
would never sell again this damaged and
deserted ship became the source of
valuable materials of which she was
stripped over the ensuing years for the
next 20 years the Liberty sat on this
Rocky black Shoreline resting in the
shadow of bali's highest volcanic
Mountain then in
1963 Mount aun erupted sending lava
earthquakes and Tremors down its slopes
to the Shoreline these Tremors CA the
Liberty to slip off the rocky Beach back
into the ocean where she lies hidden in
a watery grave to this day
[Music]
in this watery grave she continues to
serve as the infrastructure for all
kinds of life to flourish just under 400
ft long the Liberty now acts as a giant
Marine housing complex hundreds of
different marine species call her home
hard and soft corals sponges nudie
branks Crustaceans hydroids and tropical
fishes of every shape size color and
texture this dead ship is actually more
alive than ever before every piece of it
is covered with thriving life and the
creative colors of abundant Beauty this
dead ship is the reason why many divers
and explorers visit the town of tulen
boosting the local economy and providing
a meaningful living to The Beautiful
People of this
[Music]
place the Liberty was made with meaning
designed with purpose and fashion with
function her creation had a specific
intention her design was for a
meaningful objective she was used to
bring relief and fight for liberty and
freedom though she's been attacked
abused neglected and is now resting in a
watery grave her life was full of
meaning and the same is true for you
today my friend you need to know that
there's a purpose for your existence you
too were made with meaning and created
in love but this doesn't mean that life
will always be easy life on Earth is
hard just like this Rocky Shoreline and
like the Liberty living out your purpose
can be challenging there are many form
forces seeking to prevent us from living
out our god-given purpose Torpedoes
trying to sink our resolve Minds sinking
to blow up our dreams eruptions of
negative energy trying to consume
whatever is left of us the USS Liberty
lived a difficult life it endured many
attacks and persevered through much
Affliction now I don't know the storm
that you might be facing today or the
fierce battles that you're fighting that
no one else can see
but this is something that I do know
that no matter what you're facing you
can make it through it not only can you
survive but by the grace of God you can
thrive in purpose even during the most
discouraging of attacks so don't give up
and don't give
in now to the surface Observer it seems
that the Liberty's purpose ended when
she was damaged Beyond repair and left
deserted on this Rocky Beach but for me
I see that even in death her usefulness
never died her end on the beach was
really the beginning of a new phase of
meaning and usefulness At first she was
a transporting vessel then she became
the source of valuable materials and now
the remnant of her discarded wreckage is
the Gathering Place and the home of so
much light and Beauty her impact in
death is even greater than her impact in
life
just like the USS Liberty I challenge
you to live your life in the same way
that when our time on Earth is finished
and our face is seen no more that the
Legacy We Leave Behind will continue to
make a difference and that the impact of
our short existence here on Earth will
never die this is what our maker desires
for us to live in Liberty and meaning in
every changing season of life to survive
and thrive in purpose despite all the
assaults and the attacks to make a
positive Everlasting impact upon those
who see and surround us and that
whatever work Legacy and memory that we
leave behind it will continue to be a
source of beauty wisdom power and
inspiration and a tangible impact for
generations to come you can make a
lasting positive impact and it starts
with the choices that you make today big
and small the choices you make today
determine who you will be tomorrow so
let us live like the USS Liberty for a
purpose that is greater than ourselves
and a reason that reaches far beyond
after Aon for Life lived in such a way
shall never be forgotten and the impact
shall never die and may we strive to
live that kind of Life today
[Music]
what other lessons can we learn from the
history of the USS Liberty please share
in the comments below and when you have
a minute please check out the rest of
our episodes shot around the world each
is unique and special a perfect dose of
captivation exploration and inspiration
for your day see more episodes and
partner with us at the website below
your monthly pledge will Empower us to
continue creating life-changing content
for all if you'd like to join me on an
epic Excursion in Havi or create some
meaningful artistic imagery vibe to the
musings of meaningful conversations or
see more of my incredible views of
Nature and life check out my other
websites here and of course please
connect with us on YouTube Instagram and
Facebook thank you for your precious
time attention and support Aloha always
Mahalo and Marin
[Music]
welcome back living Mana church family
so happy that you could uh join us uh
today or stay with us I know I have an
echo and I think I know what to do about
it all right well that wasn't quite what
to do about
it okay that's still not what quite to
do about it so um let's
I think I know what I'm doing here
guys okay there I did it broadcast team
I didn't need you I did it on my own all
right welcome guys welcome here got rid
of that horrible Echo but glad that you
continue to uh worship with us if you're
just joining for the first time please
uh put a one in the chat but also guys
share share that invite people and
invite your social media platform uh to
church I mean have you ever invited I
don't know how many people follow you or
how many friends you have on your social
media but just think you're inviting all
of those people to church um and it's so
easy not like before if you're you're
here if you were at a brick and mortar
Church you would not be able to invite
500 people 600 a thousand who knows how
many you have like just invite them to
church and it's so very easy so please
put a one in the chat if this is your
very first time also please let us know
where you're viewing from we really want
to know uh like today we had somebody
from Serbia I hope you're still watching
with us have no idea what time it is
there but just thankful that you were
here not sure if we've had Serbia before
it didn't seem to ring a bell when I saw
it it seemed like it was the first time
so again welcome to
you uh thankful that uh this church and
this message is reaching into uh all
corners of of the world and so we're
just is thankful for that uh but again
all right we have Dallas Texas looks
like KRA from Dallas Texas welcome good
to see you here at uh living manage
church it's always a blessing to just
connect with all of you and this is
really the way uh we are able to connect
you know I was thinking about it the way
we get to like sometimes we've met you
guys in person and you tell me your name
and I'm like oh yeah your name rings a
bell because of the chat because you're
or your username or whatever you use
that is how we get to know you or we at
least uh you stand out because again
there's hundreds there's thousands after
the replays have gone who are viewing
Living manag Church but we love to see
uh people from everywhere we have Nicole
from Nashville not too far from where we
are Nicole Welcome uh to living Mana
Church good to see you here Ayana from
Trinidad and
Tobago we have Ken Mayberry from
Southern Minnesota you know what I don't
know how close you are to Minneapolis
but um that is the coldest I think I've
ever been I was there in January uh
several years ago and I remember I I got
my phone and looked at the weather and
it said negative I can't remember like I
don't know if it was like two three or
something and I thought there was
something wrong with my phone so I was
like oh no this can't be correct it is
that's how cold it was so welcome
welcome um um Kendra again from
Minnesota good to see you here uh we
have Corey from Houston all right good
to see you here welcome and Barbara from
from anguila so it's great to see you
here at Living Mana church as well guys
I just you know want to always let you
know how you can stay connected to
living Mana Church you know this is our
online church and platform but we have
amazing ways to stay connected and one
of the main ways if you are here in
America you can receive text alerts to
at least let you know when a program is
coming on when we're going live we also
send announcements that way um as well
so um please um you can just sign up for
the elmc text and that that 855 number
you want to do this if you are here in
America and you love living Mana church
and you want to stay connected and know
what's going on please do that please
because you will never miss anything and
it's really really easy the other way if
you are because we are an International
Church so if you are um somewhere else
around the world we want you and those
of you that are here in America to sign
up for mining networks because this is
our virtual Church home Mighty networks
is where you learn about the small
groups you're going to hear me do
announcements and talk about small
groups and different things but Mighty
networks is really where you're going to
learn more in depth ly about the small
groups that we have to offer the women's
group the men's group there are
different prayer uh groups going on and
other Bible study groups that are going
on and many other small groups and
that's where you're going to learn
you're going to be able to message the
the host the one that's leading other
members of the group and so if it if you
see something that interests you uh
you'll be able to do it there on Mighty
networks and that is where you form
Community because you can just get to
know everybody and talk to everybody
anytime you there's no limit no
limitations there so please join Mighty
networks because that is how you are
going to stay connected also want to
just let you know that living Mana
Church does have children's programming
and we are so thankful for our
children's programming and that's lmos
kids like you can see there on the
screen it starts at 11:30 Central on
alter live and you can get to get more
information information you can text
kids to 855 number there you can also
email the leaders that lead out in elmc
kids um at Living mana. Church and you
will get all the information that you're
going to need we have a great team of
Leaders with LMC kids they are amazing
uh they love working with your kids and
they are teaching them some amazing
things these kids are learning this is
this is a kids program but they're
learning some deep things they're doing
photo theology like Pastor Myers teaches
they're learning it at a kids level they
have crafts that they do they get very
engaged in the bi in the U Bible uh
stories and so it is something that um
if you have kids you'll want your kids
to be a part of is in LML kids and again
starts at 11:30 central time and it goes
for an hour and a half and so um I just
really encourage you to get your kids
involved you know we talked about
membership how to become a member of
living a church right at the end of
Sabbath school but just to remind you
how to become a member again you can
email Patrice living mana. live you can
ask to get your member if you are a
seventh a Adventist member already you
can get your membership transferred to
living Mana church you can ask for
profession of Faith or you can talk
about um getting baptized and so um
Patrice will help you set all of those
things up so that you can become an
official member of living man in church
and we love our viewing audience as well
but there's those who say you know what
I attend this more than I attend another
church I want to become a member here I
want to get involved and the things that
you guys have going here and so I want
to become a member and you don't have to
be a member to become to get involved in
our small groups um you can just be a
viewing audience person as well so but
that is the information if you do want
to become a member and it's always nice
to be able to talk to your pastor even
if it's uh even if your pastor is at
your virtual church and so you uh Pastor
Myers does have Virtual Office hours and
again the email is there to Patrice at
Living mana. live that is how you will
get uh set up to be able to have a
virtual office hour visit with Pastor
Meyers and you all know that living man
at church is huge on prayer like our
prayer team is they're just amazing and
so and we're so thankful for them and so
if you have a prayer request that you
would like the prayer team to pray over
you can email pray Living mana. Church
you can leave the prayer request on
Mighty Network's prayer wall or you can
text pray to the 855 number uh that you
see there on your screen and those are
the ways that you can get your prayer
requests to the prayer team and then you
can use that same uh those or that email
pray Living mana. Church when God
answers your prayers and if you want to
have that testimony shared that's where
you would send that testimony and that
that answered prayer uh to that email
Pastor Myers mentioned this as well at
the end of Sabbath school that if you
are watching on power of the Lamb
YouTube channel we would like you to go
over to living Mana YouTube channel And
subscribe there as well like And
subscribe please do that because we are
trying to grow that channel as well um
and as we have been here for almost
three years God has been blessing um and
we want even more growth so if you could
go over there and subscribe that would
be greatly appreciated we also want to
celebrate with you when it's your
birthday so to be able to do that we
need to know when your birthday is and
so uh there is um you can send your
birthday uh information in and it looks
like maybe we don't have that slide
right now but
um we will we will have that we will
have that slide for you that information
will be here probably put it on Mighty
networks I'm sure it's already there um
but we will get that to you next week um
as well so we've been asking for several
months now so we're going to continue to
ask because we're building that database
so that we can celebrate your birthday
with you now what we know that you guys
are all excited about is the
convocation so we want to give you all
the information that you need to know
about the convocation first the dates
are May 1st through 4th that's May 1st
through 4th in
Orlando um and that and as you see there
our theme is bread of life bread of life
and so that's just perfect for uh living
Mana church because we believe that the
that the Mana the word that is preached
here it is like
living bread it's the bread of life from
God's word and so it's going to be so
much fun at this convocation you do not
want to miss this convocation you get to
meet most of the leadership here that
you see on a weekly basis you're going
to be able to meet all of us we are
going to definitely get deep into the
word we're going to be worshiping and
praising God together we're going to be
fellowshipping together it is going to
be an amazing time so to get more
information to be able to register get
your rooms all of those type of things
you're going to want to scan this QR
code and um we've had it up there for
some time we continue but and also the
link is in the chat you can click the
link in the chat that will take you
directly to the website for the
convocation registration and information
you can also scan that QR code for those
again who are not familiar with how to
scan a QR code please point get your
cell pH phone point it to the QR code
open up your um camera app on your phone
and just press it like you're taking a
picture and uh it's going to um that's
going to pop up so that's how you scan a
QR code and so and if you if you're not
able to do all of that while I'm doing
the announcements you can always go back
and just do the replay on YouTube come
to this point and you can do it then um
and if you sign up to get text alerts
you're going to get this information to
you in a text if you sign up to Mighty
Networks you're going to get that
information in Mighty networks so
there's so many different ways that we
are trying to get all this information
out to you um and you're going to want
to to scan you're going to want to get
that information so that you can can be
here uh during the convocation and that
we get to uh celebrate and just to be
able to Fellowship with you um and
that's it's actually it's a month the
convocation is a month after our third
anniversary of living Mana church so it
is just perfect timing um for you to be
able uh to do that all right so our next
um announcement is there is an
LMO chrristmas party and we don't want
you guys to miss that I was I remember I
think I I was definitely there there for
the very first one and that was a lot of
fun to get to to fellowship and worship
with you guys there um and so that was
great um so we are doing the annual
Christmas party and you can see that
that's happening on the 22nd at 500m
Central to celebrate the life and
Ministry of Jesus um they will have some
fa some favorites from previous years
like Pastor poetry Bible Jeopardy and
lots of songs it's going to be a lot of
that Bible Jeopardy is a lot of fun um
and if you guys have not heard pastors
poetry well you get to hear it there at
the Christmas party so make sure that um
you will be there for that it's just a
great time to um to celebrate Jesus I
mean we should be celebrating him all
all year around but this is when the
world celebrates him and we as
Christians um join in and celebrate him
at this time as well there's also going
to be a power
Wednesday um Christmas prayer time
because I believe if I'm not mistaken
yeah I guess Christmas does fall fall on
Wednesday which is normally our power
Wednesday and so we're going to do a
Power Wednesday Christmas special the
prayer team is preparing a special
prayer service for Christmas and that's
on Christmas Day after gifts and food
have been enjoyed please come and spend
Christmas day Eve with living Mana
prayer team team and so the information
is there it's like Christmas Day at
6:30 central time so we are excited
about that as well and then there is
testimony Thursday with our own young
adult um Pastor Lami Richardson and that
starts this Thursday at 700 PM Central
Time this is for the Young Adult
Ministry and he has uh the first guest
is music artist will Alfredo and so he's
going to be sharing his testimony um on
how God has uh worked and led in his
life so you don't want to to miss that
as well we want to you know I talk about
L El OSI Global each and every week and
we thought it would be nice to be able
to show you a clip of what that looks
like because lmos Global is just like
what it sounds we have seven seven
different languages that lmlc Global
goes uh that we translate pastors
messages into these seven different
languages and we don't do it there's a
program that does it um and we wanted to
give you an example or a sample of that
of what that looks like uh because it
really is very powerful on how it looks
like Pastor Meyers is preaching um then
speaking Korean or Spanish or French um
and so it is it is a wonderful thing uh
that we are able to do here at Living
Mana church and to go into all the world
so I think we have that queued up if we
do not all right we
do for
all right so yeah that I see in the
comments you guys are like wow that's
cool and did you see that like not only
did it look looked like he was speaking
Korean but did you see the slides were
in Korean okay there you go guys that's
where all the work is right so uh we
have uh an editor that um well that's
there's a program and a system that
makes it look like it well that he's
speaking the other language so that but
the editor actually has to go in and fix
all those slides into that language so
um that takes quite a bit of time so we
are thankful uh for that so when you are
supporting LM Global you're helping um
to be able to have the editor that does
that and also the proof readers that um
that go over because we have people who
actually speak that language and
understand in English what Pastor Myers
is really saying to make sure that the
translation is correct so it takes all
of those different levels in the process
to be able to get a project like that
done so as you are praying for LM Global
and you are giving to support LM global
just remember those things that go into
it and we are just thankful and thank
you for for for just supporting all
aspects of living M church but also
these other endeavors that so that we
can go into all the world speaking the
languages of the world um and so um I'm
glad that we were able to to show a clip
so you guys could really understand what
I've been trying to say all these
several weeks and so uh that was Sister
gig's idea and it was a great idea and
um I know I can see in the comments that
that's actually been able to help you
guys get a get a grasp on what lmlc
Global is doing and so as you uh
continue to support again living Mana
church just want to remind you or let
you know if this is going to be your
first time giving how to continue or to
start supporting Levy Mana church you
can do that by going virtually this is
how you can give you can go to
adventistgiving.org you go there and you
put in you type in living Mana Church
then a tithe envelope in the right hand
corner will drop down a virtual tithe
envelope and just like the one in your
uh brick and mortar Church it looks just
like that you can give your tithe and
that your tithe goes to support uh the
northeastern conference which living
Mana church is a is is a church a member
of that conference and you can also give
your to the local church which is living
Mana church so those funds stay with
living Mana Church it helps us to do
things like lmlc global it helps us to
help uh people who are in need um
because you can give to the benevolence
fund there are so many different areas
that you can give to to support um when
you give virtually on
adventistgiving.org and so that's how
you can give virtually and another way
that you can give is to just mail in a
check if you'd like to if you don't want
to give virtually and you'd like to
write a check and send it you can do
that to the address that you see there
on your screen
and when you do that please send a note
to let us know what is for tithe what is
for offering uh where you would like
your funds that you're supporting the
church to go to specifically and then we
will make sure that it goes and it helps
in that area but we're always so very
thankful to all of you that pray for
living Mana church again we are almost
ready to celebrate our third an
anniversary on April 9th and we'll
really be celebrating at the convocation
but the fact that God has brought us
this far is is just amazing and it's a
miracle because the church is doing so
well and it's because of your prayers
and your financial gifts and you know
because we are trying to do just like
you saw we're trying to go we are going
into all the world but we're trying to
go into all the world uh with the
languages of the world you know Satan is
not happy right he could not possibly be
happy so your prayers are here to
protect prot the church it's here to
protect the church and to and to be able
to um just keep his firing Darts Away
from the church some get in and we have
to ask God to spiritually strengthen us
to be able to endure but God is always
faithful and because he is faithful and
because you are faithful to him and you
pray for this church this is why we are
still here almost three years old so we
are just again thankful to God thankful
for you for all that he is doing in this
church with all of the volunteers
there's so many of you that make this
church run it's not one person that
makes this church run there's so many
people that help to make this church run
and to all of you we are thankful we are
truly thankful and this is God's church
and his calling and he will continue to
see it through so we just want to give a
prayer of Thanksgiving just thanking God
for all his many blessings and all that
he does for this church and for us in
our personal lives God is a good amazing
God and we just want to praise him at
this time so if you please would just
bow your heads with me as we
pray Heavenly Father Lord just want to
thank you uh for God just being God you
have been so good to us you've been so
good to living Mana Church you have
helped this church get
over every hurdle that is before it and
you have been so good and then you take
us further than we even were before and
we just want to praise and thank you
Lord I want to thank you for everyone
that is viewing this service today and
everyone that will view this service um
as as they watch it later Lord I just
ask that you will bless their lives
bless them in their situations Lord
whatever they're going through help them
deal with any family issues any
Financial issues any health issues Lord
help give give them the strength help
them to make it through these times that
are so hard and difficult but Lord with
you anything is possible we can go
through anything and get through to the
other side because you are with us Lord
I just want to lift this church up to
you that you will continue to open the
doors Lord that you want us to go
through and Lord close the doors that
you don't want us to go through Lord we
want this church to be uh what you want
it to be be and to reach those who don't
know about you those who are hurting
those who just need the encouragement
those who need to understand the truth
in your word Lord because this world
this world is is is a horrible place
it's just that's just the truth it's a
horrible Place Lord and we know that we
need to be prepared to leave this earth
but we have a work to do we need to tell
so many people about your love and what
the truth in your word says Lord and so
we just pray that you would give us
strengthen us give us all the courage to
share your word and to all of those who
we know just in just in our uh those who
are around us Lord that we have an
impact on Lord in our homes at our jobs
and our family we just pray that you
will just again help us to be able to
share your message to them and Lord I
want to pray for pastor Meers just
asking that the Holy Spirit would just
give him you've already given him the
message but Lord guide his words in the
way that you want him to share it that
it will be a blessing to us all and I
ask all these things in Jesus name
amen hello I'm Hugh Wesley carington
prayer Ministries leader for the
northeastern conference in January we'll
begin our 10 days of prayer and so the
theme for 2025 is but when you pray our
10 days of Prayer Will begin January 8
2025 and we'll end with our Sabbath
celebration January 18th and so we're
encouraging you to visit www 10 daysof
prayer.org to get the readings for each
night and you need to know that the
readings are available in a variety of
languages and as we did last year for
2025 we're teaming up with health
ministries and joining me today is our
health ministries leader well I'm Joshua
deine health ministries director for the
North easn conference and I'm excited to
team up with my good friend and
colleague Dr Carrington to Kickstart
your 2025 with a happy healthy and holy
beginning in Daniel chapter 1 Daniel and
his friends chose a simple plant-based
diet they drank water and prayed three
times a day the result they were found
10 times smarter and healthier in the
New Testament the disciples prayed for
10 days in the upper room and were
filled with the Holy Spirit Well our
North American Division has declared
2025 as Pentecost 25 so we encourage you
to start the year feeling good looking
good and filled with the Holy Spirit
here are five simple things you can do
for the 10 days one eat a plant-based
diet two drink water instead of juice or
soda three walk Daily Four sleep by 10
p.m. 5 pray like Daniel those who
embrace the Daniel's diet have reported
incredible victories shedding tongs
balancing blood sugar lowering
cholesterol and saying goodbye to
brainfall you are not alone partner with
your family your friends or your church
and let's transform together start
2025 strong yes so we encourage you to
join us each night online from 7:30 to
8:30 p.m. just 1 hour you'll get health
nuggets to encourage you in your food
choices you will receive and we will
review the reading meting each night
we'll pray and praise God together
across our conference and so as we go
through the 10 days of prayer and as you
challenge yourself with the Daniel's
diet we'll also pray each night for the
North American Division Pentecost 2025
initiative so let's begin the
transformation one prayer one meal and
one step towards a healthier more
fulfilling life in Christ that's right
and so for more information visit nec's
website or NEC health.org website or
reach out to your church clerk so what
are you waiting for start your 10 days
journey of prayer and help now it's your
ticket to a happy healthy and holy
2025 let the Journey Begins
think God can't use
you think he only uses perfectly
qualified
people take a closer
look Moses was not a great
speaker Jonah ran from God
Jacob was a
liar Noah got
drunk Rahab was a
prostitute David had an
affair Jeremiah was depressed a
lot Solomon was rich in wisdom but poor
in lifestyle John the Baptist was just
plain
poor Timothy was too young Abraham was
too old
Lazarus was
dead Sarah was Barren Naomi was a widow
Gideon and Thomas both doubted and so
did Sarah Peter lacked
self-control James and John were
self-righteous Paul had a short fuse
well so did Peter and Moses actually
lots of people did
[Music]
God's Army isn't perfect it never has
been it's the march of the
unqualified get in line
[Music]
the Angels
see glory to the newb King
[Music]
the
hand
of the S of
[Music]
rightous H the Herald Angels Sing glory
to the newborn king is onor
and mercy mild God and siners
reconciled
joyful
Nations Joy the tri all
the with Angel host
Proclaim Christ is B in be the
H the h Angels Sing glory to the
[Music]
new the
newborn king
the head for Prince
of hail the son of
rightous
and
he his
wings he lays his
glory that man no more may die B to
the sons
of Born to King and second
bir the heral Angels Sing glory to the
new
[Music]
king the newn
the
newborn
[Applause]
king of the
angel I
sing the new part
H the
[Applause]
angel
[Music]
the the
newn king
[Music]
here at Living Mana we bear each other's
burdens when you need support or prayer
when you're feeling
discouraged or alone or
anxious you don't have to face life
struggles alone
[Music]
let us come boldly unto the throne of
grace that we may obtain mercy and find
Grace to help in our time of
need the Lord is close to the
Brokenhearted and saves those who are
crushed in spirit
[Music]
amen greetings Saints of the most high
God and welcome to another edition of
living man of prayer and praise time I
am brother Terry and as always here with
my lovely bride amra we are happy and
excited and thankful and just full of
gratitude for the opportunity to be able
to be with you today for worship and for
prayer and to serve God you know we've
only been we missed one week and um it
just seems like it's been a long time it
has we missed you guys yeah amen and
wanted to thank everybody for praying
for us uh the Lord pulled us right on
through the storm and uh my bride my
precious bride was Ill but uh I'll share
a little bit about that okay then amen
I'm going to let her share her testimony
of Victory and how the Lord brought her
through brought us through really
because uh we are indeed one in the Lord
and so you know today I think I want to
take a moment to do uh a a roll call a
real roll call you know I wanted to do
some shout outs first the first one I
wanted to Shout Out Sister Christina
Sister Christina we love you praying for
you the Lord has really laid you in my
heart this week and so just wanted to
let you know love you love you all
really um I'm gonna Circle back and and
really give a special shout out to my
sister Gigi really was a blessing to us
this week in a special way but brother
Robert Green saw you on the screen
earlier hey I want to shout out our chat
crew sister Ayana sister Jackie uh
sister Marisella Johnson sister
Christina's a part of that crew too
y'all are doing and it's a wonderful job
in the chat getting all the prayer
requests we thank you you're a blessing
to so many brother sister Karen right
love you saw you there brother Clint
brother holla saw you there blessing
beautiful greeting from you this morning
Elder plant saw you there everybody
sister Ramona Regina be Nicole get in
that choir girl all right all right and
um brother Anthony and Sister Janice
watching from bise you're in our
thoughts and prayers as uh your family
experienced a loss this week your
brother Robert and brother we love you
and we miss you here both you and Janice
are always going to be living man of
family we're always one in Christ so
just want to send our love to y'all and
our prayers to y'all there in
belise uh sister Tina love you sister
Tina always sister Deborah haling saw
you earlier our beloved Michelle Watson
Grant love you sister brother philli
sister Hattie always an exciting time
with you sister had brother Tennessee
saw you there brother Leon miss you my
man Maggie saw you in the chat sister
Candice B just everybody brother Andrew
Ward brother artell love you Don Val our
girl Val Hallelujah Val and Denise ebony
James Courtney and brother Graham
Hallelujah we love all y'all and just
that's a real no that was a real roll
call right there call don't all right
Sister Pauline I see you in the chat
sister Jamie from Compton see you right
there all right sister Katie oh my girl
is
fair from Sunny San
Diego you know who that is don't
you Jerry of course it's Jerry Jerry we
love you beautiful beautiful coach
Joanne you're there in the everybody
Ross and Gina is going to be hosting the
Afterglow today y'all make sure y'all
join them spend some time with them love
y'all so much sister toara I saw you
today haven't seen you in a while but uh
good to have you with us we miss you we
love you always part of living man of
family sister esterita white everybody I
I can't even
stop but I'm I'm gonna take a break we
might do a couple more shout outs here
in a minute but Amon wants to share some
praise reports some of the amazing stuff
quite a few this week okay D well I had
to do the roll call you sure well you
did that you did that that was a roll
call I'm not done oh Lord we're gonna be
here till tomorrow
folks okay before I share praise reports
just a reminder if you have a prayer
request or praise report that you would
like to share with us or you would like
to join the prayer team or a special ops
prayer team under the prayer team window
uh Umbrella Please send an email to pray
Living mana. Church if you would like to
be a part of the women's ministry in
Mighty networks please send an email to
women Living mana. Church and if you'd
like to be a part of the Men's Ministry
please send an email to seven loaves
that's s ven not the number seven seven
loaves at Living Mana church and I think
they are putting those email addresses
in the chat as we speak yes and and
since she mentioned the Men's Ministry
let me mention our beloved brother Elco
vandine from beautiful uh Cura brother
Kirk stain brother Kashif Williams and
brother Ross Brower are doing a
wonderful job leading in the Men's
Ministry so we love you all brother
Trevor we know you're always there and
brother Robert you know what brother
Jesse I know you're watching today my
man love you in the Lord uh so I just
had to squeeze those in there okay roll
call part two amen amen all right the
first praise report coming from Barbara
Simmons my grandson Alex came home after
a few week stay at an impatient
adolescent psychiatric facility for his
autism and mood disorder praise God for
his goodness and mercy thank you Jesus
amen this comes from Sheila who is is
sharing for Jazelle we have been praying
for jelle's health and employment she
has she was to start a temporary
position today but her and her son
caught some kind of virus she wasn't
able to start work today she remains
hopeful knowing we are praying for her
and her praise report was her and her
son are feeling better she was able to
leave her son with her mom while she
works and she is working now and
thanking everyone for their prayers
praise God amen from Harriet McDonald
AKA Hade amen Matthew Liams cancer tumor
has disappeared hallelujah hallelujah
amen from KS happy Sabbath church family
just wanted to thank you all for the
prayer warriors for praying for my mom
and I Health she got over covid
Glory this comes from Kashif Williams
this is the original prayer this is my
crest for my young friend Nick pray for
him and pray for his family please it
seems that Nick may have experienced a
traumatic event on campus we don't know
what when he came home from Thanksgiving
he was withdrawn morose depressed he
went back to uh school after break and
Ina told us she was worried he did not
seem himself emotionally we asked campus
police to do a wellness check they said
he was having a psychosis he was
admitted to the ER of his school Randy
and I flew down to get him and drove
back 12 hours to Maryland Nick was
confused and Afraid for us to touch him
he
flinched but then he wanted to hold
hands with us the entire car ride back
our hearts are broken as we pray for our
sweet boy we took him to the ER and the
hospital kept him for re
restabilization hopefully he will come
out of the psychosis amen praise report
prayer fixes things yes it does Nick is
doing way better looks less stressed and
worried he was looking perturbed and
anxious he is coming home next week and
it's so funny that his nurse's name is
thla and from Trinidad he's also in a
7day Adventist Hospital named Shady
Grove I told them about your prayer
group and you can tell them that he's
doing better and he's in an SDA hospital
and being cared for really well some of
the St has the same names as family
members and it's literally a sign from
God that there's support and familiarity
praise God Amen from Gigi
Jones praise report last week I gave a
praise report on how much my health had
improved in seven days and ask for
people to continue to pray that I would
be able to get a medication that would
help me pretty much change my life
initially I was told that I didn't
qualify for it then I was told I could
get it but it would be $1,400 per month
$900 with a coupon then I was told that
there was an alternative alternative
medication that was 250 per month $60
with a coupon but I didn't qualify for
it this week I had video visit with my
doctor because the really bad wound on
my leg stopped healing after the first
round of antibiotics and I started to
get sick again I prayed I've been
fasting I solicited prayers from whoever
had a heart to pray the day of the
appointment I stayed in a worship
posture just beseeching God and yet
relinquishing control knowing that he
that his will is perfect well Saints my
appointment was at 3 pm. when I tell you
everything that could go wrong went
wrong just craziness kept happening I
got disconnected twice doctor went to
the wrong room it was 4:15 before I even
saw the doctor now for me that's a
really long time I don't wait well I
kept pray even singing here and there I
even called Jesus my by his fighting
name and I said I needed Michael to come
through amen Holy Spirit brought to mind
and I reflected on when Michael said he
was late because he was busy fighting
and you know what Saints that's exactly
what was happening he was fighting for
me when the doctor finally connected it
couldn't have gone better God's face
turned towards me and shined his light
upon me she approved me for the
medication but said I didn't qualify for
insurance to pay pay for it but I was
thrilled now the medication discounted
was either going to be $30 or 60 which
is still a lot of money for me on a
monthly budget but I could do it I'm at
the pharmacy still praying that it will
be $30 and not the 60 because you know I
didn't qualify but God wasn't done
because God is the one who qualifies
because he is Jehovah Gyra because he is
Aba and giving generously to his
children the medication was free
my insurance covered it no questions no
problems someone on that prayer team
prayed a bigger prayer than I dared
someone ask for to be free I know it I'm
giving God all the glory but my sincere
heartfelt gratitude to the prayer team
and every
everyone every single person that prayed
for me Hallelujah y'all just don't know
what this means to me I have hope this
medication combined with some healthy
lifestyle adjustments is going to make a
huge difference in my life it will
enable me to embrace the health message
more fully and I can't wait to share
with you the updates and next praise
report at the convocation in a few
months what a mighty God we serve amen
listen we haven't even prayed yet but
let me tell you it is worth hearing the
mighty works of God and the way he's
working in and through the lives of his
people this church living Mana is so
amazing and our pastor and first lady
lady had the vision to build this church
and established this church on prayer
and the word just as the apostles did in
in the first church in Acts in the first
century and God has honored that that
conviction in their heart and their
desire and and we're seeing it Saints
all the time we know life is hard we
know it's not easy something's always
going on all the time amen but uh those
mountains in our life you know when
first lady was praying I was kind of
Envision in those mountains those
mountains that we face in our lives it
seems like you know Lord you're not
going to move this one out of the way
and it's blocking my view from where I'm
trying to go that mountain might be the
very thing that get us to a higher ply
to that we can see farther than we had
ever seen before God's using everything
to be a blessing and and I think you
wanted to share something else I G to
share something else about Gigi too let
me share my own praise report all right
then so just to back up and explain why
we were absent last week yeah so not
this last Wednesday but last Wednesday I
had been feeling really really sick
since shortly after Thanksgiving and I
wasn't sure what was going on I thought
maybe it was like a weird virus or flu
but after several days it wasn't getting
any better and my uh my just the fatigue
was on another level I'm
talking I had to take breaks taking a
shower because my arms were so fatigued
from just trying to wash myself I mean
it was that bad yeah and it was
continuing to get worse so Terry was
bothering me to go to the hospital and I
was being stubborn because I thought oh
I'll just go see the doctor and get a
blood test done or something she
couldn't see me right away then a tante
calls me up and she's basically saying
you need to go to the
hospital so so um Terry took me to the
ER and I'm so grateful that I went um
they just did a battery of tests they
couldn't figure out what was going on
for several hours
and they came back and said that I had
had a bladder infection that had no
symptoms at all I had no idea I had one
but that it had gone septic so I had
sepsis which is a blood infection and
luckily I was admitted to the hospital
before I went into septic shock so I
stayed in the hospital for several days
um just getting pumped with antibiotics
and fluids my kidneys took a real bad
hit
um but they're recovering so I just want
to praise God because um it could have
been much much worse and I'm feeling
about 80% now I feel much much better my
my strength and my energy is slowly
coming back I'm grateful to be here with
you today and I also want to just thank
those who really prayed for me who were
there for me who called texted Gigi sent
groceries and these roses that you see
behind me yeah she did um Gigi was such
a huge blessing sent me like seven bags
of groceries uh from the good healthy
stuff yeah she sure did um and I
received a lot of gift cards to the
grocery store and door Dash and just a
lot of love showered on me and so I just
want to thank everyone for your love and
for your prayers I know Terry was very
very worried for me um it was a rough
week it was a really rough week um but
I'm feeling much better and I just
praise God so I'm
on the the end of the road of recovery I
think yeah you know um Saints I've
learned I guess over the years to put on
a a good strong faith you know and a
good facei and uh I can a lot of times
look like nothing's bothering me but
underneath I'm like a duck under the
water and I'm constantly kicking and uh
but I want to thank God for the family
of God M POA you're always right there
in our thoughts and in our prayers we
love you and we we appreciate you I know
I was in the hospital you know and in
the hospital trying to keep a strong
facei and and you know be there for
ammer and be support for her you know
Sister Jerry I'm I'm texting with sister
Jerry and we're just you know going back
and forth about this and that and we
kind of start talking about some text
stuff on our phone little geeky stuff
that we like and and you know Jerry I
want to thank you because in that moment
you didn't even know but you were
helping me just get my mind off that
stuff you know and uh thank God for you
sis really really I love me some Jerry
and I love all of you Saints really you
know Gigi Gigi uh GG's just what can we
say you know about her she's just our
Swiss army knife everywhere all the time
in everything being a blessing
everywhere so we thank God for her
really and gig's mom's driving I just
learned that a few moments ago she's
driving all way to Orlando for the
convocation so really looking forward to
to meeting your mom GG what a blessing
look I'm I'm telling y'all I'm sitting
here lost for words really I'm saying
stuff but Harley's touching the surface
on what we see happening here at Living
Mana all the time if it's not I mean the
special ops team the prayer team
leadership blowing our minds daily with
not just the prayers but the the the the
time we spend in the word of God and if
we're over listening to pastor and we
get on the phone and we'll get stuck and
can't get off it's late night and
Amber's got to yell back to Terry get in
here you know it's um it's just amazing
what living Mana is doing God is doing
in and through living Mana so family we
love y'all stay on board the ship of
Zion God is bringing us on through he's
working in us and through US
straightening us out getting us ready
for that great and glorious getting up
morning and so thank you all for your
very kind messages in the chat I see
them and I appreciate them so much so
thank you so much and it's so good to be
back it's so good to be back here it is
it is and so one of the things that
we're doing also here um is you know
when God called me into the ministry of
intercessory prayer I always assumed it
would always be a Ministry of obscurity
because prayer is where I spent most of
the time praying in my prayer closet and
God taught me to pray in my prayer
closet where nobody's looking and
nobody's listening except for maybe one
correctional officer who held his keys
and snuck up on the door in the closet
while I was praying and and I heard him
out there a couple times and he was
listen he knew I prayed and you know he
wrote about that in my central file so
what you do in private God will reward
openly and anyway but but when I came
here God is doing a different thing with
prayer and our prayer warriors are very
visible they're seen power Wednesday or
they're in the chats praying and we're I
mean God is being glorified through
what's happening here so what we like to
do is we like to bring on prayer
warriors and um and and and allow you to
see sometimes who's behind the scene
really praying and interceding for you
and standing in the Gap today we're
going to bring our special sister our
blessed sister Annette Rivas I mean and
she is really on fire always there she's
there at Power Wednesday she's doing the
graphics she's working with sister
Angela she's working with the women's
Min just everywhere doing everything and
so sister Annette as you come to lead
today in intercessory prayer we want to
praise God for you and thank you today
amen amen I believe sister Net's coming
up
now e
or go to settings and set your default
mic
okay well unfortunately for the moment
if we're going to take up prayer and if
she comes in just go ahead and cut us
right out and let her begin to pray but
together Saints let's go to to the
throne of grace and um father we just
want to thank you today Lord for being
here with us here at Living Mana for
being so awesome for being so mighty and
being so powerful and being so good Lord
in the name of Jesus we come today we
just want to offer up a prayer of
Thanksgiving now there are a lot of
prayer requests in the chat and we know
you see them all and we know that the
Warriors are getting them our prayer
warriors in the chat have been praying
as soon as these prayer requests pop up
in that chat they pray for them even
right there and so together as your
people right now we want to bow at the
throne of grace Lord it is easy to come
to you with petitions on our heart
because we're always going through
something we're always experiencing
something but oh Lord God we want to
thank you that on this day we remember
that you have made provision for us even
before the foundation of the world
Hallelujah you are indeed the lord of
the Sabbath and God we thank you that
today as we enter into your rest no
matter what we are facing no matter what
we are experiencing Lord you are Alpha
and Omega the beginning and the end the
first and the last you've gone before us
you've seen us and you have made
provision for it and so we rest in you
today and we say thank you oh God thank
you for salvation thank you for healing
thank you for deliverance thank you for
comfort and for being a shelter in the
time of storm oh God thank you for being
a friend that sticketh closer than a
brother thank you for being a lion of
the tribe of Judah giving us courage to
do what is right even if there is
challenges standing before us thank you
when you there are insurmountable odds
you are the god of impossibilities Lord
God thank you for being a light in a
dark place thank you for regulating our
mind oh Lord when we had questions and
confusion and chaos and Trouble on all
sides oh Lord God thank you that you are
our peace thank you that you are Our
Hope Lord bread when we're hungry thank
you that when we were broke Lord we
wasn't all the way broke CU you made a
way out thank you for showing us favor
when the bills were stacked so high and
we were worried about how we going to
pay them and you gave us favor and the
medication was free Lord thank you for
being the doctor in the do in the
hospital room thank you for healing us
of cancer thank you for driving out
demonic principalities and powers and
obsessive thoughts Lord God thank you
for breaking the chains of habits and
addiction in our life oh God thank you
Hallelujah Lord God when we thought that
our life was over and thought we'd made
such a mess of it that we can do nothing
with it Lord but you came and made this
broken vessel again another as SE
pleasing in your eyes thank you for
being the master Potter thank you for
being the master physician and the
carpenter that's building this house and
building this Kingdom oh Lord and
rebuilding Our Lives thank you for
making us a new creation in Christ Jesus
oh God thank you for making us not just
conquerors but more than conquerors in
Christ Jesus thank you that nothing
shall separate us from the love of God
that is in Christ Jesus today thank you
for giving us power to to trample on
serpents and scorpions and over all the
power of the enemy and that nothing
shall any means hurt us Lord thank you
that when we're backed up into a corner
we bump into goodness and mercy because
your word said goodness and mercy shall
follow us all the Days of Our Lives
Hallelujah in Jesus name we praise you
and bless you that you are a miracle
worker a way maker a promisee keeper a
mighty God you show up and make a way
when there is no way just because we
don't see a way don't mean you ain't
about to make one thank you for giving
us the strength to endure and hold on
through the storm oh Lord God in Jesus
name thank you that you make all things
beautiful in your time Hallelujah God we
want to just go down our list today we
know we don't have enough time to thank
you for everything You' done done we
don't even know all you have done God
you've been keeping us from danger seen
and unseen you are worthy to be praised
we lift you up here at Living Mana today
and we magnify you we glorify you we
praise you we exalt you for you are
worthy oh God not just because of what
you do not just because of the things
you give us we worship you because you
are God because we are yours we enter
into your presence today with
Thanksgiving in our hearts and into your
court with praise oh God hallelujah
somebody said when the Praises go up the
blessings come down then shower them
down lord today because we giving you
glory in this house today we giving you
the honor and the praise the only thing
we want to ask for you in this hour Lord
is grant us the the holy ghost that the
eyes of our understanding might be
enlightened open our eyes so we can see
how good you are so we can praise you
some more in this place today God in
Jesus name and thank you Father
Hallelujah that you know how to keep us
from falling and to present us faultless
before the presence of Your Glory thank
you that you got our children in your
hands thank you that you got our futures
in your hands our careers our jobs our
Ministries our gifts our calling our
anointing everything in your hand Lord
Lord God and you've given us that thank
you that your word says that the gifts
and callings of God are irrevocable
without repent you ain't going to take
it back thank you that you're not like
folk fall out with you and then cut you
off not you God you're faithful
Hallelujah faithful to the end and thank
you that your love has pursued us when
we didn't even want to do right you told
us to go left we went right told us to
go right we went left Lord told us to
move we set still but yet God your love
has overcome us and overpowered us and
for that today we give you glory honor
and praise somebody wanted to hear their
specific prayer mentioned today I pray
that they would know that in the courts
of Heaven there's no such thing as a
silent prayer but there's not a word in
our mouth except you know it all
together even before we speak Hallelujah
you already sending the answer and so we
give you glory today and we give you
honor with this prayer of Thanksgiving
let the words of our mouth and the
meditation of our heart be acceptable in
your sight oh Lord our Rock and Our
Redeemer May our prayers today be set
before you as incense oh Lord and may
the lifting up of our hands be as the
evening and morning sacrifice God we
thank you we bless you and Praise You
Lord in all the little troubles all the
little obstacles all the little barriers
all the little breakdowns breakups and
breakouts that we experience God we want
to thank you today that you're are
greater you're greater than it all Lord
and so we give you praise we give you
glory and we give you honor and the
waiting in Jesus mighty and Majestic
name all God's people declare amen amen
amen
hallelujah and
sister
I
will lift up my eyes to the
heels from whence come my
help my Help Cometh
From The
Lord the Lord which made Heaven and
Earth
he
said he will not suffer thy
foot thy foot to be moved
the Lord which
[Music]
keep he will not
Slumber
sleep
for
the Lord is thy
keeper The Lord Is Thy shame
[Music]
upon thy right
hand
no the sun shall not smite thee by day
of the Moon by
night he shall
preserve my
soul even
for
[Music]
more
my
[Music]
my my
all of my Help Cometh for
all
the Lord
[Music]
amen church happy Sabbath welcome uh to
all of you that are watching I want to
go ahead and uh just uh invite you to uh
hit that share button and uh let people
know that the message is about to begin
uh and uh today beloved we're going to
be continuing our time of trouble series
um we're going to be talking about the
nine essential things
necessary for the time of
trouble and so I'm going to invite you
to pray with me we're going to jump
right into the message today um let us
seek the Lord's face and presence uh to
prepare us to receive his word let's
pray Heavenly
Father please I ask Lord that you would
take the message you have given me
and Lord speak through
me May these
words be crafted and guided by
you and speak to our hearts Lord is our
prayer in Jesus name amen amen put that
one in the chat if you are ready to get
into the word of God this
morning um we're going to go ahead and
go to our first slide going to go ahead
and go to our first slide uh once again
again this is the time of trouble series
part
three part one was love part two was
joy and today we're addressing the third
essential
required for the time of
trouble in Revelation 7 verse
1 the Bible says and after these things
I saw four Angels standing on the four
corners of the Earth holding the Four
Winds of the earth that the wind should
not blow on the earth nor on the sea nor
on any
tree and I saw another Angel ascending
from the East having the Seal of the
Living
God and he cried with a loud voice to
the four angels to whom it was given to
hurt the Earth and the sea saying hurt
not the Earth neither the sea nor the
trees till we have
sealed the Servants of our God in their
foreheads the Bible
describes this event of the four these
four Angels holding back the Four Winds
of
Heaven until the people of God are
sealed until the people of God are
prepared to stand when those winds are
let loose and so it is critical to
understand that only those who have the
Seal of God only those who have been
sealed are the ones that are
prepared to stand in the crisis to stand
in this time of trouble and so our
question naturally becomes what does it
mean
to be sealed by God in the book of
Ephesians chapter
4 in the book of Ephesians chapter 4 we
are
told and grieve not the holy spirit of
God whereby you are sealed unto the day
of
redemption the Bible lets us know that
it is the holy spirit of God that is
responsible
for sealing God's
people the holy spirit of
God is the
agency the holy spirit of God is the
person that SEALS or
prepares those who will stand to stand
and the way that the Holy Spirit does
this is by infusing himself into the
individual so so that the individual
Bears the fruit of the
spirit what is the fruit of the spirit
the fruit of the spirit is love it is
Joy it is
peace it is longsuffering it is
gentleness it is goodness it is Faith it
is meekness it is temperance these are
the nine
Essentials required to stand in the time
of trouble
in our part one we addressed the
essential of
love in part two we addressed the
joy and today we're going to be
addressing the essential of
Peace in the time of trouble Satan is
going to test your joy he's going to
test your
love and today we're going to learn that
he's going to
test your
peace
remember the Holy Spirit seals God's
people and that sealing revolves around
the
character of God being replicated in us
meaning love joy peace longsuffering
gentl goodness Faith meekness
Temperance those who are sealed are
reflect refecting the character of God
but we also understand that in symol
form the
seal is
itself the
Sabbath now you may Wonder well Pastor
how are you about to connect the Sabbath
and and and the the the the Holy Spirit
ceiling and what we're talking about
today peace how are you going to connect
that we know that in Ezekiel 20 and
verse 12 the Bible says moreover
also I gave them my
sabbaths to be a sign between me and
them that they might know that I am the
Lord that sanctify them the
Sabbath is the sign or the
seal between God and his people and we
need to understand the reason
why if if you
if you have ever heard how the the Jews
bring in the Sabbath they will often say
something two words um can you tell me
what those two words are put those words
in the chat for me please if you can
repeat those
words when the Sabbath comes in they say
something they
say
sabat come on everybody what do they say
they
say
shabat I'm waiting for
it I'm waiting for it in the
chat all right let me just beat there
you
go now can you tell me what that means
shabbat shalom what does that mean what
does
Shalom
mean shalom
means come on y'all put it in the
chat the fruit of the spirit is
love it is
Joy it
is
peace the Seal of
God which is given by the Holy Spirit
signifies that we have been settled in
love in joy and today we're going to see
in peace the Sabbath is a symbol of
peace let me let me demonstrate to you
come back with me to the
screen and let's go to Genesis chapter 1
Genesis chapter 1 beginning with verse
one the Bible says in the beginning God
created the heavens and the Earth and
the Earth was without form and void void
and darkness was upon the face of the
deep and the spirit of God moved upon
the face of the waters so in the
beginning the Earth was in a chaotic
State put that word in the chat for me
please the Earth was in a chaotic state
it was disorderly there was chaos uh
there was no form it was void it was
darkness and then we know that the
spirit of God is the is the person that
begins to move upon the face of the
waters and and and and then the creation
process begins now what's happening in
this creation process is that the Earth
is moving from a state of
chaos to order and
peace and so what we find is that at the
end of this process
according to Genesis chapter 2 here's
what the Bible says thus the heavens and
the Earth were finished and all the host
of them and on the seventh day God ended
his work which he had made and he rested
on the seventh day from all his work
which he had made and God blessed the
seventh day and Sanctified it because
that in it he had rested from all his
work which God created and made the
Sabbath was the was the symbol that the
Earth had moved from
chaos to a place of
Peace are y'all with me so far put a one
in the chat if you're with me so far the
Sabbath was the was the sign the sealing
sign that the Earth had move from a
condition of chaos and disorder to a
condition of order and
peace and so it is no wonder that the
Sabbath is the
sign of
Peace in fact I want you to note with
me that the Bible says in Isaiah chapter
8:1
16 bind up the testimony
seal the law among my disciples we
understand that the Seal of God revolves
around the law of God of which the
Sabbath is highlighted that Sabbath says
peace those who stand in the time of
trouble will be standing in peace put a
one in the chat no no no I'm sorry y'all
already putting ones put a two in the
chat if you're saying pastor that's me I
want to be able to stand in
peace I want to be able to stand in
peace the Bible says bind up the
testimony seal the law among my
disciples now why is this so significant
because I want you to note the next text
Psalm 1191 165 the Bible says come on
y'all read it with
me
great
peace have they that love thy law and
nothing shall offend them so hold on the
Holy Spirit seals is the sealer
in sealing us the holy spirit is is is
is sealing the character of God in us
what is the character of God it is the
fruit of the spirits the fruit of the
spirit is love joy peace long-suffering
gentl goodness Faith meekness Temperance
but we're focusing today on peace which
becomes very significant because we
realize wait the Seal of God we
understand is the Sabbath the sign that
something has moved from
chaos to order and
peace God
rested in
peace God rested when he finished
creating the world and now it begins to
make sense because the Bible says seal
the law among my disciples seal the law
among my disciples
H those who have the law sealed upon
them the same Bible says great peace
have they which love thy law and nothing
shall offend them the Sabbath is the
symbol of peace now why is this so
crucial why is it so crucial to
understand that God is trying to seal Us
in peace let me show you why let me ask
you a question what is the opposite of
Peace what is the opposite of
Peace what is the opposite of Peace
we're going to go to Daniel 12 verse1
let me see if you can identify what is
the opposite of Peace as I read Daniel
12:1 the Bible says and at that time
shall Michael stand up the great Prince
which standeth for the children of thy
people
and there shall be a
time
of
trouble such as never was since there
was a nation even to that same time and
at that time thy people shall be
delivered everyone that shall be found
written in the book there shall be a
time of trouble beloved listen to me the
opposite of peace is war the opposite of
peace is trouble the opposite of peace
is chaos and so what I want you to
understand here is that in a time when
the world is going to be chaotic when
the world is going to be at Strife when
the world is going to be in disorder
when the world is going to be in a time
of trouble such as as never was those
who are sealed in God will be
experiencing put it in the chat
yall they will be
experiencing
peace I like that third
Angel how about we greet each other on
Sabbath saying hey man rest in
peace rip rest in peace that's what the
Sabbath is it is teaching us how to rest
in peace despite the chaotic week that
we may have been through God says listen
I'm training you every seventh day I'm
training you how to stand in peace as
they say today 10 10 toes 10 toes stand
in
peace come on y'all
so now now now we can begin to
understand why Jesus said these words
Jesus said Peace I leave with you my
peace I give unto you not as the world
giveth give I unto you let not your
heart be troubled neither Let It Be
Afraid you see how can Jesus say that
why would Jesus say that the reason
Jesus is saying that especially as it
relates to the time of trouble is that
in the time of of trouble if you don't
have the peace of God in your heart your
heart is going to be
troubled so Jesus says I leave my peace
with you beloved listen to me the final
Conflict at the end of time will be a
conflict between War and Peace those who
have the spirit of War versus those who
have the spirit of peace this is why the
Bible says in Revelation 12:1 17 and the
dragon was wroth with the woman and went
to make
war with those who because they love the
Commandments of God have peace did y'all
see what just
happened great peace have they which
love thy law nothing shall offend them
so the dragon is going to make war with
the woman and to make war with the
remnant of those which keep the
Commandments of God and therefore
profess to be walking in
peace the dragon is going to go to war
with watch this according to Matthew 5:9
blessed are the
peacemakers for they shall be called the
children of God
did y'all catch
that the dragon is going to make war
with the
peacemakers according to Isaiah 32:17
the Bible says and the work of
righteousness shall be peace the work of
righteousness shall be what shall be
peace and the effect of righteousness
quietness and Assurance Forever This is
why Jesus says in Matthew 11: 28 Matthew
11:28 he says come unto me all ye that
labor and are heavy laden and I will
give you
rest I will give you
peace so now that we be can begin to
understand the ramifications of what
we've learned so far we can now begin to
see that the devil's goal at the end of
time will be to stir up the spirit of
War
against those who have the spirit of
peace did y'all catch
that in the time of trouble we learned
last week that the devil when the Four
Winds are are loosed the devil's going
to test the joy of the redeemed the
devil's going to test the love of the
redeemed there are nine different ways
in which the redeem are going to be
tested in which the the the remnant are
going to be tested when those winds are
let loose do you really have
love do you really have the joy of the
Lord do you really stand in
peace yes yes yes yes he's he's going to
attempt to SP stir up the spirit of
Wrath and the spirit of war in those who
claim to be peacemakers
and beloved you can see him doing it now
put a one in the chat if y'all can
relate to what I'm saying right now you
could see him doing this now I'm going
to give you an example from the Bible
come with me to the Book of Luke Chapter
9ine I'm going to tell you I'm going to
show you just how the devil seeks to do
this the Bible says in Luke 9:51 and it
came to pass when the time was come that
he should be received up he steadfastly
set his face to go to Jerusalem and he
sent Messengers before his face and they
went and entered into a village of the
Samaritans to make ready for him and
when they did not receive him because
his face was as though it would go to
Jerusalem or and they did not receive
him because his face was set as though
he who go through Jerusalem and when his
disciples James and John saw this they
said Lord will thou that we command fire
to come down from heaven and consume
them even as Elias did but he turned and
rebuked them and said you know not what
manner of spirit you are of for the son
of man has not come to destroy men's
lives but to save them and they went to
another Village I want y'all to catch
What's Happening
Here the
disciples in what they consider
righteous
indignation want to wipe out the
unbelievers want to wipe out out those
who reject Jesus want to wipe out those
who don't follow the words of Jesus want
to wipe out those who are who are openly
against Jesus want to wipe out those who
are living Lifestyles against Jesus want
to wipe out those who won't submit to
the word of God want to wipe out those
who claim that God does not exist they
want to wipe out the atheist they want
to wipe out they are angry with
them in the name of
righteousness and God Jesus rebukes them
and says you know not what manner of
spirit you are of what manner of spirit
were they of they were of the spirit of
War yes beloved yes beloved this is why
Jesus is called the Prince of Peace
according to Isaiah 9:6 listen to me
this is the very thing that Satan will
attempt to do and he will do it under a
disguise of
righteousness so that you think it's
fine to be angry with those who disagree
with you it's fine to be angry with with
the Heathen it's fine to be angry with
the Godless world yeah yeah yeah it's
fine and yet beloved those who fall for
this will as surely be swept away when
those four winds are let
loose because if you lack in love in any
one of these nine Essentials if you lack
in love if you lack in Joy if you lack
in peace those winds when they are let
loose will blow you
away it will carry you away I need you
to understand that Jesus is our example
in peace notice with me Matthew chap 26:
26 and the high priest arose and said
unto him anwers thou nothing what is it
that these false Witnesses these false
which these witness against
thee but Jesus I'm going just pause
right
here I'm I'm just gonna pause right here
I'm gonna let y'all fill in those next
two words but Jesus what three words I'm
sorry but
Jesus come on everybody what did Jesus
do what does Jesus want us to
do Jesus
held his
peace let me say it again Jesus held his
peace now yes in the context it simply
means that he was quiet he was he did
not allow them to Rouse him but I need
you to understand beloved the the
powerful significance of those three
words when it says Jesus what held his
peace at the End of Time Beloved the
test is going to be how well are we able
to hold our peace in fact the Bible
tells us in Exodus chap 14 verse 14 the
Bible says the Lord shall fight for you
and you shall
what come on somebody help me you shall
what you shall hold your
peace so I need you to understand
beloved that the devil's going to
attempt to get you to let go of your
peace but you got to be firm and hold
your peace so the question then is how
do we hold our peace how do we hold our
peace listen to what the Bible says in
Ephesians chapter 2: 13 but now in
Christ Jesus you who are sometimes far
off from
God were made nigh by the blood of
Christ for he is our peace who has made
both
one and broken down the middle wall of
partition between us beloved to hold our
peace is to hold Jesus
W did y all catch that just now to hold
your peace is to hold
Jesus because he is our
peace he is our
Prince of
Peace and now what I want you to
understand when the Bible says that he
is our peace what it means is he is our
peace between us and
God because remember sin brought enmity
Warfare between us and God so Jesus
through his blood becomes our peace
therefore the Bible says in Romans 5:1
therefore being justified by faith we
have
peace with God through the Lord Jesus
Christ through our Lord why is he our
peace because through him we now have
peace with
God we are no longer at War
with God there is no longer chaos
between us and God there is peace in
fact Ezekiel
37:26 calls it literally moreover I will
make a covenant of peace with them it
shall be an Everlasting Covenant it is
the Covenant of
Peace how fitting then that the Holy
Spirit whose fruit is peace should
decide to seal us with the
Sabbath which literally is a symbol of
peace which literally is a symbol of no
more
chaos how powerful is
that so if I have peace with God then I
will be able to stand in the time of
trouble without my heart being troubled
the the reason my heart will not be
troubled is because my heart has been
sealed and is standing in
peace yes yes what I'm saying beloved is
that we need to pray for peace we need
to pray for joy we need to pray for love
and that's is what I'm saying is we need
to pray for the spirit because when the
spirit is truly in us then beloved we're
going to manifest it by by manifesting
love and manifesting joy and manifesting
peace and the Holy Spirit seals us with
these things so at the End of Time the
devil's going to be like no they don't
really have the spirit and I'm gonna I'm
going to prove that they don't have the
spirit I'm G to come Lord you allow me
to test their love you allow me to test
their Joy you allow me to test their
peace I'mma bring on a time of trouble
and let's
see let's see how they do in this time
time of trouble you see beloved Isaiah
48:22 is absolutely true the Bible says
there is no peace sayeth the
Lord there is no peace sayeth the Lord
unto the
wicked why is there no peace because it
is obvious that the wicked have not
grabbed hold of peace they have not
grabbed hold of Jesus and because they
have not grabbed hold of Jesus there is
no peace between them and God and when
you have no peace you you turn to the
spirit of War listen to
me I do not care if you are in the
church one of the greatest evidences
that you have no peace that you do not
have Jesus is that you embibe in the
spirit of War
God
beloved God beloved is calling us to not
let go of
Jesus much
like Jacob y'all remember him let's go
to the screen in Genesis 32 verse 22 the
Bible says Jacob Arose that night and he
took his two wives and the two women's
servant and his 11 sons and passed over
the four Jabbok and he took them and
sent them over the brook and sent over
that he had and Jacob was left alone and
there Wrestled a man with him until the
breaking of the day and when he saw that
he prevailed not against him he touched
the hollow of his thigh and the hollow
of Jacob's thigh was out of joint as he
wrestled with him and he said let me go
for the day breth and he said I will not
let thee go except thou bless me beloved
with the same passion that Jacob had
where he said I will not let thee
go that is how we ought to fight did
y'all hear what I just said that is how
we ought to fight for our
peace so many of us are busy fighting
perceived enemies and not fighting for
the peace of God and what's that what
that is showing beloved is that we have
let go of Jesus and are fighting our own
battles making our own
demands shall we burn them down God you
stay back we got this they what they
offended you they they disrespected you
they don't they don't want to bow down
to you all right you stay right here God
we'll be right back not realizing that
those who embe in the spirit are eming
in the spirit of War it is a sign that
they have let go of Jesus which is their
peace and and embraced a spirit of war
and this is exactly what the devil will
do at the very end of time and in fact
he is doing it
now in fact he's doing it now what I
need you to understand beloved is that
God desires you to rest in his love in
fact in fact if you turn with me to uh
to Zephaniah notice this Zephaniah 3:17
notice what the Bible says here the Lord
thy God in the midst of thee is mighty
he will save thee he will rejoice over
thee he will rest in his love do y'all
know that word rest
means that word rest is actually peace
in the Old
Testament the words are used
interchangeably and what he's saying is
that he will rest in he will will have
peace in his love what does it mean that
God will rest in his love God is it's
almost as if God is saying listen my
love is so deep and Broad and certain
for you that I rest in it and if I can
rest in my love I want you to rest in my
love that's how you get
rest when you can rest
assured that I got you when you can rest
assured that that that I love you then
you're walking in peace when you can
rest assur that I got your battles then
you can rest in peace now the Lord's
going to fight this for me when you can
rest in peace you're not taking the
situation into your own hands I need
y'all to check this out y'all remember
that story in The Book of Mark chapter
35 where the Bible says in the same day
when the evening was come he saith unto
them let us pass over unto the other
side and when they had sent away the
multitude they took him even as he was
in the ship and there also were other
ships with him y'all remember the story
and there were Rose a great storm of
wind and the waves beat into the ship so
that it was now full it seemed like
these winds were blowing in every
direction a and and this storm had hit
them and and and notice what happens the
Bible says and he Jesus the prince of
peace he Jesus who is our peace he Jesus
was in the hinder part of the ship
asleep and to add insult to injury it
the Bible literally adds in on a pillow
as
if as if it wasn't amazing enough that
he was
asleep we just need to throw
in that he was sleeping on a
pillow you know what a person looks like
when they're sleeping on a
pillow your comforter you just you just
comfortable everything is
good how are you
sleeping on a
pillow a comfortable
pillow a comforting
pillow a comforter pillow that's what a
pillow is it's a comfort for your
head how many of you would like comfort
for your
heads how many of you would like comfort
for for
your heads something to rest your head
on the Bible says and they awake him and
say unto him Master carest thou not that
we perish and he arose and rebuked the
wind and said unto the sea come
on peace be still and the wind ceased
and there was was a great calm beloved I
believe I believe I believe that in the
time of trouble the redeemed will have
power to say to the winds that are
blowing about peace be
still why because they're going to have
a Divine
pillow oh man how many of you want that
Divine pillow how many of you want that
rest for your heads for your mind how
many of you want that seal of that
pillow how many of you want that that
peace yes yes Chris Christian that peace
of
mind how do you get that peace of mind
Jesus says I will give you a peace of my
mind now listen y'all when somebody says
I'm gonna give you a piece of my mind
they're usually mad about it let me I'm
GNA give you a piece of my
mind Jesus says it and means something
totally
different he says I want to give you a
piece of my mind not I'm going to I want
to give you a piece of my mind I want my
mind to be in you because if my mind is
in you through the work of the Holy
Spirit you're going to have that
comforter you're going to have that
pillow and in the time of storms when
the Four Winds are blowing and everybody
is panicking and their hearts are
troubled you have a Divine pillow and
you are you are at
peace you're at peace on that pillow
y'all that
comforter Peace of
Mind Peace of
Mind
resting in
peace resting in peace resting in God's
love resting in God's joy resting in
peace I need yall to understand that
that the opposite of peace is chaos it
is violence it is disorder it is
hostility it is tension and the devil
wants to bring all this to the heart of
man to the heart of God's people in a
time of trouble but God says as long as
you have this pillow you will be all
right in the storm let the winds come
Let the Rain Fall let the floods come
you will be all right you will be able
to rest in peace now watch this y'all
this is why the Bible says in Mark 13:7
this is what Jesus says this is what
Jesus says listen
listen in Mark 13:7 she he says this and
when you shall hear of wars and rumors
of wars be not troubled for such things
must be but the end shall not be yet do
you know what be not troubled means that
word for
troubled that word for troubled
literally means the word troubled I
should say literally means means
clamor and the word clamor means a loud
and Confused noise especially that of
people shouting vly listen to what Jesus
is saying
y'all when you hear of wars and rumors
of wars don't let your heart get caught
up in the spirit of war and rumors of
War put it put that put that one in the
chat if you followed what I just
said in other words when the world
around you is trying to get you riled up
Lord have
mercy when the world around you is
trying to get you riled
up be angry at these people
because watch out for those people
because when the world around you is
trying to in is trying to infuse into
you the spirit of clamor the spirit of
War let not your heart be
troubled
no know that I am not in
that know that I am not in that the
devil is going to try to bring that into
your hearts and he's going to try to
bring that into the church why because
he wants to destroy the church so that
those who should be peacemakers are at
War
with one
another he says let not your heart be
troubled why is it significant because
the Bible warns us of this very thing
listen Revelation 11:18 and the nations
were angry and thy wrath has come that
the time of the Dead that they should be
judged what's happening with the
Nations the Bible is telling us that the
nations are going to be angry but God
says I need you to hold your
peace I need you to hold your peace come
on come on Revelation 18 verse1 notice
what the text says and after these
things I saw another angel coming down
from heaven having great power and the
Earth was lightened with his glory and
he cried mightily with a strong voice
saying Babylon the greatest Fallen is
fallen and has become the habitation of
devils and the hold of every foul spirit
and a cage of every unclean and hateful
bird
for all
nations have drunk
of the wine of the
what of the wrath of her
fornication did y'all catch
that all nations are going to be
angry and if all nations are going to be
angry then I need you to understand that
Satan is going to try to get you angry
too he's going to try to get you caught
up in the spirit of of the world he's
going to try to get you caught up in the
spirit of anger and he's going to try to
dress it up as righteous anger I am
angry at all the the way that the world
is going going to shambles and look at
these people who are just turning our
nation away from God I am angry and the
devil doesn't care how he puts the
spirit of Wrath in you whether under the
context of evil or under the context of
I'm a Jesus Lover he doesn't care if he
can get you to start being
angry listen All
Nations have drunk of the wine of the
Wrath this parallels something
absolutely stunning y'all because in the
same chapter Revelation 18 verse verse
verse 23 the Bible says and the light of
a candle shall shine no more at all in
thee and the voice of the bridegroom and
of the Bride shall be heard no more at
all in thee for thy Merchants were the
Great Men of the Earth for by thy
sorceries were all nations deceived wow
wow so all nations were deceived by
sorcery but in the upper part of that
chapter it says all nations drank of the
wine of the Wrath I need y'all to
understand that the sorcery is the wine
of the Wrath put a five in the chat if
y'all caught what I just said the
sorcery is the wine of the
Wrath it is not just false
Doctrine it is the spirit of the Wrath
of the world and the Prof even the
professed Christian
world that God's people begin to take on
themselves that the devil wants God's
people to take on themselves now now I'm
about to break something down to you and
we're almost done but I need you to
follow this follow this carefully watch
this watch this the Bible says in
Revelation 13:1 17 that no man might buy
or sell save he that had the
Mark or the name of the Beast or the
number of his name now let me ask you a
question put it in the chat for me
please what is the mark of the
beast what is the mark of the
beast We Believe believe that the mark
of the beast
is an
enforced
law it's an enforced law against the
Commandments of
God that's what we believe particularly
the fourth Commandment a counterfeit of
the fourth Commandment a counterfeit day
that will be enforced by law which
people are talking about now but I need
y'all to understand something here
the text says that no man might by
yourselves save he that had the Mark or
the
name it's as if the verse is saying
listen we're not only wor we don't just
worry about the mark you can also get
the name of the
Beast now what I need y'all to
understand beloved is that name in the
Bible names in the Bible are symbolic of
character so when you see name think
character the name of the Beast would be
parallel would would would be pointing
to the character of the
Beast yeah y'all put a nine put a nine
in the chat if you're following the name
of the Beast would parallel the
character of the
Beast the name of Jesus is the character
of Jesus the name of the Beast would be
the character of the beast that's how
the Beast is
identified in Revelation CH 3:12 the
Bible says him that overcometh I will
make a pillar in the temple of my God
and he shall go no more out and I will
write upon him the name of my God and
the name of the city of my God which is
New Jerusalem which cometh down out of
Heaven from my God and I will write upon
him my new name I need you to see that
this seal of God really is the name of
God which means the character of God the
city of
God New
Jerusalem and Jesus's new
name come on y'all listen listen listen
Revelation 14:1 says this and I looked
and low a lamb stood on Mount Zion with
him 144,000 having the father's name
written in their foreheads meaning the
father's character is written in them
and what is the character it is a fruit
of the spirit love joy peace
longsuffering gentl goodness Faith
meanness Temperance that is the
character of God
those who are sealed in the forehead
have a they have a pillow a Divine
pillow yeah yeah now now y'all know how
we always say right the Seal of God a
seal would be the the name the title and
the territory right you know how we say
that right and we say that seal is found
in the Sabbath the Lord thy God creator
of Heaven and Earth I want you to see
that's the very thing that we see
described in Revelation chapter 3 when
God when Jesus says I will write upon
him the name of my
God and the name of the city or
territory of my God the New Jerusalem
let me ask you a question what does
Jerusalem mean what does the word
Jerusalem literally
mean
city of what
do y'all see that in order to have the
name New Jerusalem written upon you city
of Peace you must be a citizen of
Peace in order to have the city of Peace
written upon your forehead you must you
must be a citizen of peace
now watch
this in Revelation chapter
18 the Beast which is here described as
a woman also
has a mark something written on her
forehead she's simply identified as the
mystery mystery it just says mystery but
we know what mystery this is this is the
mystery of iniquity which the Bible
tells us is Satan
himself
title
mother
territory
Babylon seal of
God name
father title Creator territory New
Jerusalem those giving over to the
devil who is he he is the mystery of
iniquity
title symbolically mother
territory
Babylon the Bible says in second 2
Thessalonians CH 2: 7 and8 for the
mystery of iniquity doth already work
only who not lth will let until he be
taken out of the way and then shall that
Wicked be revealed whom the Lord shall
consume with the spirit of his mouth and
Destroy with the brightness of his
coming the Bible says in Revelation 174
and5 and the woman was arrayed in purple
and scarlet color and decked with gold
and precious stones and Pearls having a
golden cup in her hand full of
Abominations and the filth of her
fornication and upon her forehead was a
name written beloved listen
everybody's going to have a name written
on their foreheads at at the End of Time
symbolically speaking and you will
either have the city of Jerusalem
meaning the city of peace or the city of
Babylon meaning the city of
confusion the city of
chaos it is the character of the Beast
the city of anger the city of
War come on y'all here here we're we're
we're almost there we're are y'all doing
okay we're almost there follow this
y'all in Galatians chapter 5:20 we're
about to read The Works of the flesh
versus the fruit of the spirit and I
want you to notice what Galatians 5:20
says it says these are the works of the
flesh
idolatry and we're going to skip
idolatry I want you to notice these next
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 eight
words
witchcraft hatred variance emulations
wrath Strife seditions heresies now
check this out check this out but the
fruit of the spirit is love joy peace
longsuffering gentl goodness Faith
meanness Temperance against such there
is no law now here are the words y'all
that we just read about witchcraft what
is it the word is phia it means
medication the mind is medicated the
word listen to me
sorcery
witchcraft here here hold on let me go
to the next word let me go to the next
word so the next word is is
hatred hatred
it means opposition enmity variance the
next
word
variance contentions debate Strife
variance emulations the next
word
emulations it means
Envy fervent mind
indignation jealousy
Zeal the next word
wrath it
means fierceness indignation R the next
word
strife and listen to this one
y'all
Strife means
Intrigue and the word Intrigue means to
arouse the Curiosity or interest or to
Fascinate
Intrigue stuff other people don't
know instead of having
peace those who are under the
flesh
Thrive off of
intrigue yo yo
yo those who are of the flesh
thrive on
division those who are of the
flesh thrive on
emulations they thrive on all these
things whereas those who are of the
spirit thrive on
peace the devil beloved is seeking to
infect the Church of
god with the spirit of war with the
spirit of strife with the spirit of
contention with the spirit of intrigue
all in the name of
Jesus we can't forget this this last
word
heresy
heresy check out the definition for
dissension
division sedition
the act of taking or capturing storming
a
city the spirit of
storming
power the spirit of
takeover beloved I want you to
understand that this will be the very
Spirit of the entire world at the end of
time and how did they get there because
the devil was able to just feed them l
little by little this Same Spirit under
the disguise of righteousness or in open
wickedness he was able to feed them the
same spirit so much so that the Holy
Spirit was being grieved and pushed away
and pushed away and it will get to the
point that when the spirit of God has
been totally removed from the Earth all
you will have is a people who are bent
on the spirit of War
notice how Galatians 5 the same chapter
that we're in notice how galatian 5 ends
it says and they that are Christ have
crucified the flesh with the affections
and lust if we live in the spirit let us
also walk in the spirit let us not be
desires desirous of vain Glory provoking
one another envying one
another those who are sealed
I'm not going to be doing the things of
the
flesh what does Ephesians 4 actually say
after it says grieve not the holy spirit
of God whereby you are sealed unto the
day of redemption then it the next words
let all bitterness and wrath and anger
and clamor and evil speaking be put away
from you with all malice do y'all see
this those who are sealed by the Holy
Spirit have put away bitterness wrath
anger clamor evil speaking they' put it
away from them along with malice so then
here is what this clearly shows us those
who
emide in evil speaking and anger and
bitterness and wrath and whether you
think you have the right to be angry at
the church or angry at this person or
angry at that person because they're
ungodly and they're they need you when
you engage in that Spirit go ahead and
call yourselves sons of thunder
but don't take that as a statement of of
Glory don't take that as because Jesus
said you know not what manner of spirit
you
are the text goes on to say be ye kind
one to another tender-hearted forgiving
one another even as God for Christ's
sake has forgiven you
all right y'all this is
it you know how Satan tried to get
Jesus let let's read it Matthew 27:38
then were two thieves crucified with him
one on the right hand the other on the
left and they that passed reviled him
wagging their heads and saying thou that
destroy the temple and build it in three
days save thyself if thou be the Son of
God come down from the cross they trying
to R Jesus up likewise also the chief
priest mocking him with the scribes and
Elders said he saved others himself he
cannot save if he be the king of Israel
let him now come down from the cross and
we will believe him they tried to R
Jesus up he trusted in God let him
deliver him now if we will have him if
he will have him for for he said I am
the Son of God the thieves also which
were crucified with him cast the same in
their teeth I need y'all to see that
they were attempting to take Jesus's
peace but Jesus held his peace
and the reason is
simple our closing text For unto us a
child is born unto us a son is given and
the government shall be upon his
shoulders and his name Shall be Called
wonderful
counselor the Mighty God the Everlasting
father the
Prince of
Peace beloved we can neither choose the
Prince of Peace
or we can choose the prince of this
world we can either
have the Divine
pillow which will give us
rest for our
heads where the name of God and the City
of
God New
Jerusalem the city of Peace written only
upon the heads of its City
cens because they are
peacemakers they're
peacemakers we can either have the name
of God written in our foreheads or we
can have the name mystery Babylon we can
have that name signifying who's we
belong who we belong to the spirit of
confusion the spirit of
war the spirit of anger when those four
winds are let loose
there's no more time for
Preparation those who have been em
bibing in the spirit of
peace will be
asleep will have peace in the
storm and those who have spent their
time searching
out
War those who have spent their time em
bibing in the spirit of
War will be found
wanting the
winds will blow you
away and so my appeal today the appeal
of the spirit
today is to
pray for the pillow
Lord grant me that
comforter that I may learn how to sleep
that I may learn how to
rest when all kinds of craziness is
going on around me help me to hold my
peace just as Jacob held his peace and
would not let his peace go until he
blessed him if that's your desire I want
you to put a nine in the chat put a nine
in the chat because we want those nine
Essentials for the time of trouble you
put that nine in the chat while I pray
Heavenly Father we thank you for
speaking to us Lord we thank you for
speaking peace into our
lives Lord may we not adopt or embibe in
the wine of the Wrath of the enemy may
we not have the name may we not be
citizens of baby
citizens of chaos citizens of of
War please
Lord teach
us to truly be
peacemakers Lord not the false
peace but the spiritual
peace so that when that time of trouble
hits be it a small time of trouble now
or the big time of trouble then
that we will be able to rest on the
comforter rest our
minds in
peace in Jesus name we
pray
amen and
amen praise God for all the Nines in the
chat we're going to go ahead and put the
link for the uh uh after glow the after
discussion on altar live so for those of
you that would like to join us and uh
and fellowship uh please feel free to do
so may God bless you as you continue to
plead and pray for the spirit of
peace to be a reality in your in your
life in Jesus name again we pray
amen thank you for joining us today if
this is your first time worshiping with
us please check out our website at
Living mana. Church we are not just here
for Sabbath service we have weekly
programming too that covers mental
health physical health weekly prayer
service Financial Health and proving the
existence of God it is our desire that
our programming will continue to bless
you please continue to pray for us as we
fulfill God's mission to go into all the
world with the Gospel of Jesus Christ
[Music]
e e